well
良い
then
それから
family
家族
And muscle sig
そしてマッスルシグ
euro
ユーロ
okay
わかった
all
全て
Good night
おやすみ
Today we are very happy to invite researcher Wang Zhonghe
本日は研究者の王忠和氏をお招きできることを大変嬉しく思います
Let's help us interpret a topic that has been very, very lively recently
最近非常に活発になっているトピックを解釈するのを手伝ってみましょう
How to deal with global warming was held in Paris about a month ago
地球温暖化にどう対処するかが約1か月前にパリで開催されました
So today Dr. Wang can help us very well. How should we respond personally?
今日、王博士は私たちをとてもよく助けてくれます。私たちは個人的にどのように対応すべきでしょうか?
He will explain the data very clearly
データをわかりやすく説明してくれる
Dr. Wang's expertise is in stable isotropic geochemical analysis
王博士の専門知識は安定等方性地球化学分析です。
Dr. Wang is now a researcher at the Earth Institute
ワン博士は現在、地球研究所の研究者です
He is also the director of the secretariat of our Academia Sinica
彼は私たちの中央研究院の事務局長でもあります。
so he should be very busy
だから彼はとても忙しいはずだ
Come on one night and tell us about these things
ある晩来て、これらのことについて話してください
Grateful
非常感激
Well, his research field is actually very broad.
そうですね、彼の研究分野は実に広いです。
It has a lot to do with climate warming
気候温暖化と大きく関係している
There is still water temperature before the warming environment
温暖化環境に入る前の水温がまだある
I believe you often see him on TV too
テレビでもよく見かけると思います
Talk about the issue of water resources
水資源の問題について話します
The precursor of the earthquake and so on
地震の前兆など
This is all within the scope of his research
これはすべて彼の研究の範囲内です
He graduated from campus university in 1984
彼は 1984 年にキャンパス大学を卒業しました
I returned to Taiwan after getting my Ph.D.
博士号取得後、台湾に戻りました。
just go back to Academia Sinica
中央研究院に戻ってください
So he is also in Academia Sinica
それで彼は中央研究院にも所属しています
30 years
30年
32 years
32年
Well, not only is he here, except for the Academia Sinica
まあ、中央研究院を除いて、彼はここにいるだけではありません
He is also in the National Taiwan University Center for Global Change
彼は国立台湾大学グローバル変化センターにも所属しています。
National Chengchi University General Studies Center
国立政治大学総合学習センター
central university
中央大学
Hydrology and marine science research units
水文学および海洋科学研究ユニット
part time
パートタイム
So what I read just now is related to his specialty.
つまり、私が今読んだ内容は彼の専門に関連したものです。
So later if you are interested
興味があれば後ほど
Can
できる
you can ask him well
彼によく尋ねることができます
The topic he gave us today is global warming and disaster prevention and response
今日のテーマは「地球温暖化と防災とその対応」
So what we just said about this summit in Paris
さて、パリでのこのサミットについて私たちが今言ったこと
to talk about global warming
地球温暖化について話すために
How to deal with disasters has not been mentioned
災害時の対処方法については言及されていない
OK, we welcome Dr. Wang
OK、王博士を歓迎します
Thank you to the vice president, the secretary-general, Mr. Li, and all the distinguished guests.
副大統領、李事務総長、そして来賓の皆様に感謝申し上げます。
Colleagues
同僚
It is my great honor to be present at our Knowledge Feast in January 2016 today
本日、2016 年 1 月に開催されたナレッジ フェストに出席できたことを大変光栄に思います。
Let everyone be the first to report our climate warming
気候温暖化を誰よりも早く報告しましょう
A trend we now call global warming
私たちが現在地球温暖化と呼んでいる傾向
And the impact we will face under this trend
そして、この傾向の下で私たちが直面するであろう影響
what we should have
私たちが持つべきもの
First of all, let me review with you
まずは一緒に復習していきましょう
our past year
私たちの過去1年
we all say 2015
みんな2015年って言うよ
it is our earth has history
私たちの地球には歴史があります
Since the temperature measurement
検温してから
hottest year
最も暑い年
this year
ことし
we just said
私たちはただ話したばかりだと言いました
We use five indicators to tell you
5 つの指標を使用してそれを伝えます
why is it so unique
なぜそんなにユニークなのでしょうか
Its first uniqueness is
その第一のユニークさは、
it was in 2015
それは2015年のことでした
concentration of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere
大気中の二酸化炭素の濃度
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
Here is February 2015
こちらは2015年2月
The following is 14
以下は14です
The next step is 13
次のステップは13です
That is, it is February every year
つまり毎年2月です
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
most importantly
最も重要なこと
how much it rises every year
毎年どれくらい上がるのか
about two to three units
2～3台くらい
Then in 2015 it has several characteristics
そして2015年にはいくつかの特徴があります
the first is
一つ目は
It is the concentration of carbon dioxide in the air
空気中の二酸化炭素の濃度です
Has broken through 400 units
400ユニットを突破しました
For the first time in 3 million years
300万年ぶりに
it not only says
それは言うだけではありません
Breaking through 400 units this month
今月400台突破
In fact, there are a total of 8 months in 2015
実際、2015 年は合計 8 か月あります。
Both broke through our 400 units
どちらも当社の400ユニットを突破しました
This is our past human history
これは私たちの過去の人類の歴史です
not available in the market
市場では入手できません
We just saw February March
2月3月を見たばかりです
it's april
4月です
then may june
それから5月6月
Then the next thing is
それでは次は
it's july november december
7月11月12月です
So you can see here a series of
ここで一連の様子を見ることができます
all told us
みんなが私たちに言いました
8 months of the year break through
一年のうち8か月が突破口
This carbon dioxide has exceeded 400 units
この二酸化炭素は400単位を超えています
this is very unique
これはとてもユニークです
Then we are all a witness to history
そうすれば、私たち全員が歴史の証人になります
This is the first anomaly indicator
これは最初の異常インジケーターです
The second indicator is just said
2番目の指標は今言われたばかりです
2015 is actually the year we started in 1850
2015 年は実際には 1850 年に始まった年です
A very accurate measure of the temperature dependence of the Earth's surface
地球表面の温度依存性の非常に正確な測定値
It has the highest global temperature
地球上で最も気温が高い場所です
As you can see, this is the year
ご覧のとおり、今年は
from 1850
1850年から
this is the temperature
これが気温です
temperature is the outlier
温度は異常値です
Its baseline is the average from 1961 to 1990
ベースラインは 1961 年から 1990 年の平均です
We can see that
それがわかります
It is probably the highest after this time
おそらくこの後が最高値でしょう。
It's just that 2015 was the hottest year since Dominance
2015 年はドミナンス以来最も暑い年だったというだけです
This is the second indicator
これは2番目のインジケーターです
the third is
3つ目は
on the east side of our Pacific Ocean
私たちの太平洋の東側で
There is also a sound phenomenon
音の出る現象もある
The sound phenomenon is to the east of the Pacific Ocean
音現象は太平洋の東です
The temperature of sea water is very high
海水の温度はとても高いです
This time the sound phenomenon is caused by
今回の音現象の原因は、
Since 1950, we have actually been since the 20th century
1950 年以来、実際には 20 世紀から
The strongest sound phenomenon we have ever observed
私たちがこれまでに観測した中で最も強い音響現象
This time not only the temperature of our ocean is very hot
今回は海の温度が非常に暑いだけではありません
It affects all our atmospheres
それは私たちのあらゆる雰囲気に影響を与えます
and the interaction between the atmosphere and the ocean
そして大気と海洋の相互作用
also affects a climate on all of Earth's
地球全体の気候にも影響を与える
This sound phenomenon so far
これまでのこの音現象
still in development
まだ開発中です
It will make our climate this year come
それが今年の気候を変えるでしょう
Will bring some variables that we can't imagine
私たちが想像できないいくつかの変数をもたらすでしょう
Below you see the green
下に緑が見えます
Blue is anti-sound phenomenon
青はアンチサウンド現象
Then this time after the sound ends
そして今度は音が終わってから
We'll be ready for the next backlash
私たちは次の反動に備えます
This is the third indicator
これが3つ目の指標です
The fourth indicator we just got from the atmosphere
大気から得たばかりの 4 番目の指標
then into the ocean
それから海へ
it's still ocean
まだ海です
The fourth indicator is the global sea level
4 番目の指標は世界の海面です。
Global sea level since 1993 we started
1993 年に開始して以来の世界の海面
MSI is a very accurate measure of the average height of sea level on our planet's surface
MSI は、地球の表面の平均海面高を非常に正確に測定したものです。
We can see from 1993 to October 16, 2015
1993年から2015年10月16日まで見ることができます
that's the last bit
それが最後の部分です
then throw up
それから吐く
Our sea levels have risen by more than 8 centimeters
海面は8センチ以上上昇しました
in such a short time
こんなに短い間に
Over 20 years, our sea level will increase by 8 cm
20年間で海面は8cm上昇する
Probably the entire past twentieth century
おそらく過去20世紀全体
double in a century
1世紀で2倍になる
so this is a very high number
これは非常に高い数字です
But everyone can see
でも誰でも見れるよ
The last curve is still accelerating
最後のカーブはまだ加速中
it means
その意味は
In the future, the sea level will continue to rise
今後も海面は上昇し続けるだろう
and it will be faster
そしてそれはより速くなります
This is the fourth very unusual indicator we see
これは非常に珍しい指標の 4 つ目です。
The fifth is actually very far away from us
5番目は実際には私たちから非常に遠いです
This is the origin of this Arctic Oscillation
これが北極振動の起源です
is our arctic ocean
私たちの北極海は
The Arctic Ocean in March last year
昨年3月の北極海
Here's an indicator of what we saw in mid-March last year
これは昨年 3 月中旬に観察されたものの指標です
Its ice cap area is the white part
氷冠部分は白い部分です
Only 14 million square kilometers
わずか1,400万平方キロメートル
This is us from 1979
これが1979年の私たちです
The lowest record since the start of measurement
測定開始以来最低記録
In 1979 we measured here
1979年にここで測定しました
We can see it slowly slide all the way down
ゆっくりと下まで滑り落ちていくのがわかります
it's winter
冬です
Winter is the largest location of Arctic Sun
冬は北極太陽の最大の場所です
There are more than 1000 square kilometers
面積は1000平方キロメートル以上あります
But March 2015 was the lowest since Dominance
しかし、2015年3月はドミナンス以来最低だった
only 14 million
たったの1400万
In the past you can see more than 16 million
過去には1,600万件以上を見ることができました
Such a phenomenon is expressed by saying that
このような現象を次のように表現します。
When its winter ice cover becomes smaller
冬の氷が小さくなってくると、
its summer will be more serious
夏はさらに深刻になるだろう
I will use the data to make a report with you
データを使用してレポートを作成します
These five indicators all tell us that
これら 5 つの指標はすべて次のことを示しています。
2015 was a very unique year
2015 年は非常にユニークな年でした
this unique year
このユニークな年
From our atmosphere to our oceans
大気から海洋まで
to this far edge of ours
私たちのこの遠い端まで
all told us
みんなが私たちに言いました
The earth has happened a lot and there is no way
地球にはたくさんのことが起こったが、仕方がない
Things I didn't see before
以前は見えなかったもの
these things can happen
これらのことは起こり得る
Mainly because we changed
主に私たちが変わったからです
Some important factors in our earth
私たちの地球におけるいくつかの重要な要素
One factor is the greenhouse gases in our large estates
要因の 1 つは、広大な敷地内の温室効果ガスです。
we can use carbon dioxide
二酸化炭素を使うことができます
Its concentration is an indicator
その濃度が指標となる
Mainly look at
主に見るのは
This is our earth's distant past
これは私たちの地球の遠い過去です
Our present is at the last point
私たちの現在は最終地点にあります
We look at the past 100,000 years
過去10万年を振り返る
two hundred thousand years
二十万年
three hundred thousand years
30万年
four hundred thousand years
四十万年
The concentration of carbon dioxide in our atmosphere
私たちの大気中の二酸化炭素の濃度
it rises and falls naturally
自然に上がったり下がったりする
it will be high
高いでしょう
it will be low
低いでしょう
it will be more
もっと多くなるだろう
it will be less
それは少なくなります
It's like the coat of our earth
それは私たちの地球のコートのようなものです
but it's more
しかしそれ以上です
it also has an upper limit
それにも上限がある
The upper limit is about 300 units
この上限は約 300 ユニットです
it's the lowest
それは最低だ
about 180
約180
That is to say, they differ from each other
つまり、それらは互いに異なります
About 100 units
約100台
As long as the 100 units change
100単位が変わる限り
the climate of our planet
私たちの地球の気候
From Warm Ages to Ice Ages
温暖時代から氷河期へ
Or from the ice age and back to the warm period
あるいは氷河期から温暖期に戻る
So only need to change 100 units
したがって、100 単位を変更するだけで済みます
The climate of our planet will be completely changed
私たちの地球の気候は完全に変化するでしょう
But now our human influence
しかし今では私たち人間の影響力が
It's the blue line at the back
後ろの青いラインです
This line we amplify it
このラインを増幅します
This is the line you see above
これは上に表示されている行です
We've been real since 1958
私たちは1958年から実在しています
The CO2 concentration in the air has been so low until now
空気中のCO2濃度はこれまで非常に低かった
when we only see one thing
一つのことしか見えないとき
It's in our atmosphere
それは私たちの大気圏の中にある
us
私たち
The concentration of breathed carbon dioxide is constantly increasing
呼吸した二酸化炭素の濃度は常に増加しています
to this year's
今年に向けて
Either this year or last July
今年か去年の7月か
Has broken through 400 units
400ユニットを突破しました
It is also the highest ever
こちらも過去最高です
The annual average for 2015
2015年の年間平均
It will also break through 400 units
400台も突破します
But it keeps going up
でも上がり続けてるよ
You can see the one we just released
先ほどリリースしたものをご覧ください
This indicator for each month
この指標は月ごとに
its annual growth rate
その年間成長率
It is a big increase of 2 to 3 units compared with last year
昨年に比べて2～3台の大幅な増加です
According to a rate like this
このようなレートによると
if we don't make any changes
何も変更しなければ
it will be before 2038
2038年より前になるだろう
will break through a very important critical point
非常に重要な臨界点を突破するだろう
called 450 units
450ユニットと呼ばれる
Once the 450 orders break through,
450件の注文を突破すると、
Our planet will bring unimaginable results
私たちの地球は想像を絶する結果をもたらすでしょう
Our temperature will rise very fast
私たちの体温はとても早く上昇します
The change we face
私たちが直面する変化
It's all beyond our imagination
それはすべて私たちの想像を超えています
So we human beings in such a
ですから、私たち人間はそのような状況にあります
Under the circumstances we made two mistakes
このような状況下で、私たちは2つの間違いを犯しました
The first mistake is
最初の間違いは、
We broke a natural ceiling
私たちは自然の天井を打ち破った
And break through very fast
そして非常に早く突破します
From 200 to 300 in the past
昔は200から300まで
it only increases by 100 units
100単位しか増えない
Earth is from an ice banner
地球は氷のバナーから
You flipped all of a sudden to a very warm ice age
突然、非常に温暖な氷河期に切り替わったのです
it only takes 100 units
必要な単位は 100 単位だけです
We have now added another 100 units
さらに 100 ユニットを追加しました
You can see us from 300 before the industrial revolution
産業革命の300年前から私たちを見ることができます
278 We've reached 400 units now
278 400台に到達しました
So we added 100 units in a very short time
したがって、非常に短期間で 100 ユニットを追加しました
So we're not only breaking a natural upper limit
つまり、私たちは自然の上限を突破しているだけではありません
And we increase the number rate 100 times that of nature
そしてその数率を自然の100倍に高めます
We used to go from 200 to 300 and it took us 20,000 years
かつては 200 年から 300 年に到達するのに 20,000 年かかりました
It takes 20,000 years to naturally increase
自然に増えるには2万年かかる
Now we only spent 200+ years
今、私たちが費やしたのはわずか200年以上です
So we use the data rate of nature at a very fast speed in the slave
したがって、スレーブでは非常に高速な自然のデータ速度を使用します。
This disturbs the ecosystem of our entire planet.
これは地球全体の生態系を乱します。
That is what we are facing today
それが今日私たちが直面していることです
Some changes we haven't seen, thought, or heard of in the past
これまで見たことも、考えたことも、聞いたこともなかったいくつかの変化
In this picture, it tells us that
この写真からわかることは、
The mistakes we made were very, very horrific
私たちが犯した間違いはとてもとても恐ろしいものでした
also very stupid
とても愚かでもあります
The left is a natural state
左が自然な状態
this is our earth
ここは私たちの地球です
we have a very important atmosphere
私たちはとても重要な雰囲気を持っています
It has very precise concentrations of greenhouse gases
非常に正確な温室効果ガス濃度が含まれています
The CO2 is one of the guards with this
CO2 はこれを守るガードの 1 つです
Oxygen Nitric Oxide, the first pill, is measured with a concentration of one part per billion
最初の錠剤である酸素一酸化窒素は、10億分の1の濃度で測定されます
In the past, its changes were very limited.
以前は、その変更は非常に限定的でした。
And it goes up and down within a very limited range
そしてそれは非常に限られた範囲内で上下します
It holds the sun to our surface
それは太陽を私たちの表面に保持します
Heat energy can be intercepted at our surface
熱エネルギーは地表で遮断できる
warm the earth
地球を温める
but not too hot
でも暑すぎない
Then it's going to decrease a little
そしたら少しは減りますよ
It emits a little more heat
もう少し熱を発します
our earth will be cold
私たちの地球は寒くなるでしょう
but not too cold
でも寒すぎない
But now everything has changed
しかし今ではすべてが変わってしまった
that's what we are now
それが今の私たちです
Because after two hundred years of influence
なぜなら、200年にわたる影響力を経て、
Our pan-nitrogen oxide
当社の汎窒素酸化物
Pill A and Oxygen Nitric Oxide both increased significantly
錠剤と酸素と窒素酸化物の両方が大幅に増加しました
The rate of increase is very fast
増加速度は非常に速いです
It is a hundred times that of nature in the past
過去の自然の100倍です
and it increases the amount
そして量が増える
also surpassed our past
過去も超えた
This undulating quality between ice cream and ice cream
アイスとアイスの間のこの波打つ質感
Now we hold the sun up to
今私たちは太陽をかざします
Our surface traps very, very much heat
私たちの表面は非常に多くの熱を閉じ込めます
So the thermal energy temperature of our surface
したがって、私たちの表面の熱エネルギー温度は
I watched it never go up
決して上がらないのを見た
Not only does it mean that the heat coming in from the outside cannot go out
外から入ってくる熱が外に出なくなるだけではなく、
The endotype of the earth inside us is actually a temperature exceeding
私たちの内部の地球のエンドタイプは、実際には温度を超えています。
Humidity 6000 degrees
涉溼六千度
It actually used to go through this long distance
実は昔はこんな長い距離を通っていたのです
From the cold in the sky to the crust
空の冷たさから地殻まで
and then radiate through the thick layer into our outer space
そして厚い層を通って宇宙空間に放射されます
now it can't get out
今は出られない
So now we actually have two incoming thermal energies
したがって、実際には 2 つの熱エネルギーが入ってきます。
one is from outside
一人は外から来た
we keep it
私たちはそれを保管します
One was supposed to go out from inside
一人は中から外に出る予定だった
can't go out now
今は外出できない
stay on the surface of our crust
私たちの地殻の表面に留まります
So now our greenhouse gas
それで今、私たちの温室効果ガスは
The amount of heat accumulated on our surface is staggering
私たちの表面に蓄積される熱量は驚異的です
How amazing is it?
どれくらいすごいのでしょうか？
Later we have the actual data
後で実際のデータが得られます
This is what we have on the surface of the Earth today
これが今日の地球の表面にあるものです
all the way to the sea and all the way to our land
海まで、そして私たちの土地まで
what we observed
私たちが観察したこと
There are 10 indicators on this
これには10の指標があります
In these 10 indicators
これら10の指標では
7 all told us that
7人全員がそう言いました
Our temperature is increasing
私たちの体温は上昇しています
one is the temperature of the atmosphere
1つは大気の温度です
One is the humidity of the atmosphere
一つは大気の湿度です
One is the sea surface temperature
一つは海面水温です
sea ​​surface temperature
海面温度
heat in the ocean
海の熱さ
Plus the temperature of our land is also increasing
さらに、私たちの土地の温度も上昇しています
So we are now from air to sea to land
だから私たちは今、空から海、そして陸へ
that's even scarier
それはさらに怖いです
Our sea level increases with temperature
私たちの海面は気温とともに上昇します
it will expand
それは拡大します
And our mountain glaciers
そして私たちの山の氷河
melting all the time
ずっと溶けてる
it comes in
それは入ってくる
it flows into the waters of our ocean basins
それは私たちの海洋盆地の水に流れ込みます
always rising
常に上昇中
So we just saw that there is a fourth indicator that is sea level
4 番目の指標として海面があることがわかりました。
rising faster and faster
ますます速く上昇する
that helps us regulate the temperature
それは私たちが体温を調節するのに役立ちます
In addition to the high mountain and the two-level edge
高い山と二段の端に加えて
and snow
そして雪
and the beach inside
そして中のビーチ
It is like our earth's natural freezer
それは地球の天然冷凍庫のようなものです
But their numbers are decreasing
しかし、その数は減少しています
Their functions are also slowly shrinking
彼らの機能も徐々に縮小しつつある
The impact on us will be more and more
私たちへの影響はますます大きくなるでしょう
So we look at these indicators
そこで、これらの指標を見ていきます
like what
どのような
like we did a physical today
今日身体検査をしたように
We failed all the indicators
すべての指標が失敗しました
our snow duck
私たちの雪アヒル
our snow hall
私たちの雪の館
our cholesterol
私たちのコレステロール
We're failing every measure of our health
私たちは健康のあらゆる基準を満たしていません
That's what we're facing on Earth today
それが今日私たちが地球上で直面していることです
This is the IPCC
これがIPCCです
It's the Intergovernmental Commission on Changing the Name of the Post-7th Generation
それはポスト7世代の名前変更に関する政府間委員会です
it was in 2013 to 2014
2013年から2014年にかけてでした
It released two pictures in the fifth post-Qi commentary report
斉後の第5回解説レポートで2枚の写真を公開した
we'll just put it here
ここに置きます
tell everyone
みんなに言ってください
Because we accumulated so much heat
たくさんの熱を蓄えたから
Now we do scientific observations
今、私たちは科学的観測を行っています
we saw the unfortunate truth
私たちは残念な事実を目の当たりにしてしまいました
That is, the temperature of our surface continues to rise
つまり、私たちの表面の温度は上昇し続けます
This is from 1850 until
これは1850年から
it's 2012
2012年です
From 1850 to 2012
1850 年から 2012 年まで
we can see a fact
私たちは事実を見ることができます
is the rate at which our entire planet's surface rises
私たちの惑星の表面全体が上昇する速度です
probably once
おそらく一度
This is the first one
これが最初のものです
In the past, the earth would rise by one degree
昔は地球は1度上昇した
It drops by one degree, in fact, it will adjust itself
1度下がります、実際には自動的に調整されます
but it goes up one degree
でも1度上がる
it better take 5000+ years
5000年以上かかるほうがいい
We only spent 150 years now
私たちが過ごしたのはまだ150年だけ
So we not only say
だから私たちはただ言うだけではなく、
increase the amount of greenhouse gas accumulation very much
温室効果ガスの蓄積量が非常に増加する
Our woods are growing very fast
私たちの森はとても早く成長しています
We've also seen our temperatures rise
気温も上昇しています
also very amazing
とても素晴らしい
Even more terrifying is the picture below
さらに恐ろしいのは下の写真です
This picture is the temperature of 10 years
この写真は10年の温度です
do an average
平均をする
so you see a square
それで正方形が見えます
is the average temperature every 10 years
10年ごとの平均気温です
its black part
その黒い部分
It is the average value in the past 10 years
過去10年間の平均値です
past we see
私たちが見る過去
Cubes with mean temperature per 10 years
10 年ごとの平均気温を持つ立方体
it will all overlap
すべてが重なり合うだろう
It goes up and down very slowly
とてもゆっくりと上がったり下がったりします
But since 1980
しかし、1980年以降、
We've seen the situation change completely.
私たちは状況が完全に変化するのを目の当たりにしました。
Since 1980
1980年以降
we can see the temperature
私たちは温度を見ることができます
Every 10 years is a bouncing rock
10年ごとに跳ねる石
it will never again
それは二度とないだろう
Relatively together, they will not overlap
比較的一緒なので重なりません
So what does this jumping up signify?
では、この飛び上がることは何を意味するのでしょうか？
means that our temperature is not only rising
それは私たちの体温が上昇しているだけではないことを意味します
And the rise is accelerating
そして上昇は加速している
This is what we are facing now
これが私たちが今直面していることです
So our temperature is still increasing
だから私たちの体温はまだ上昇中です
Our rate of temperature increase is accelerating
気温の上昇速度は加速しています
This is what we observe now
これが私たちが今観察していることです
Next, we are not only talking about our past
次に、私たちは過去のことだけを話しているのではありません
we can see our future too
私たちにも未来が見える
This is what the IPCC stated in its Fifth Assessment Report
これはIPCCが第5次評価報告書で述べたことです
another picture
他の写真
it allows us to see us now
それは私たちに今を見ることを可能にします
our past and our future
私たちの過去と未来
Our past is what we just said
私たちの過去は今言ったことです
This is from 1950 to our present
これは1950年から現在までです
We see that the temperature keeps rising
気温が上昇し続けていることがわかります
So we in this generation
ですから、この世代の私たちは、
in the process of our growing up
私たちの成長の過程で
We are all witnesses of history
私たちは皆歴史の証人です
We've all seen this temperature keep rising
気温が上がり続けるのを私たちは皆見てきました
But we look from now to the future
しかし、私たちは今から未来を見ます
we only see one fact
私たちが目にする事実はただ一つだけ
No matter what kind of energy reduction and carbon reduction we adopt
どのようなエネルギー削減や二酸化炭素削減を採用しても
or do this temperance work
それともこの節制の仕事をするか
Here, of course, the IPCC has made four different
ここで、もちろん、IPCC は 4 つの異なる方針を作成しました。
This scenario simulates
このシナリオはシミュレーションします
What we want most is of course this
私たちが一番欲しいのは、もちろんこれです
just please blue
ただ青くしてください
Then there is a strong energy reduction and carbon reduction
次に、強力なエネルギー削減と炭素削減が行われます。
It keeps our temperature going up
それは私たちの体温を上げ続けます
just be slow
ただゆっくりしてください
But others, no matter whether it is low-medium or high-medium
ただし、それ以外の場合は、低中程度か高中程度かは関係ありません。
don't even make any changes
何も変更しないでください
It will be even more astonishing as our temperature rises
気温が上がるとさらに驚くことになるでしょう
This picture only tells us one thing
この写真が伝えていることはただ一つ
We do any energy reduction and carbon reduction
私たちはあらゆるエネルギー削減と炭素削減に取り組みます
well done we still have to go up
よくやった、まだ登らなければならない
It's just that the rise is less and the rise is slower
ただ、立ち上がりが少なく、立ち上がりが遅いです
we didn't do well
私たちはうまくいきませんでした
Our future temperature rise
私たちの将来の気温上昇
it will be very very amazing
とてもとても素晴らしいことになるでしょう
In other words, our future
つまり、私たちの未来は、
at least before 2000
少なくとも2000年以前には
what we can't change
私たちが変えられないもの
Can not be changed is the temperature will not rise
温度が上がらないので変更不可
temperature will continue to rise
気温は上昇し続けるだろう
only through our efforts
私たちの努力によってのみ
will slow down the rate of rise
上昇率が鈍化するだろう
it hit us less
それは私たちにあまり影響を与えませんでした
if we don't make any changes
何も変更しなければ
Then the impact we bring will be very, very large.
そうすれば、私たちがもたらす影響は非常に大きなものになるでしょう。
Where are the shocks?
ショックはどこにありますか？
That's what I'm going to tell you
それが私があなたに伝えたいことです
Speaking of which means we used to go
そういえば昔行ってたな
Because the temperature has risen by one degree like this
こんな感じで気温が1度上がったので
what we are facing
私たちが直面していること
If we continue to rise in the future
今後も上昇し続ければ
at least once
少なくとも一度は
or one and a half
または1年半
or more than two
または2つ以上
Our increased exposure to shocks
ショックにさらされる機会が増える
probably far more than
おそらくそれよりはるかに多い
our imagination today
今日の私たちの想像力
This is when the IBCD was in 2014
これは IBCD が 2014 年に開催されたときのものです
It reports a picture inside
その中の写真をレポートします
This picture is very important
この写真はとても重要です
where does it matter
どこが重要ですか
What we just showed you is an indicator of temperature.
先ほど示したのは温度の指標です。
It is an indicator of thermal energy
熱エネルギーを表す指標です
Its heat energy unit is amazing
熱エネルギー単位がすごい
One unit is the 10-21 power glue ear
1台は10-21パワーグルーイヤーです。
how big is this
これはどのくらいの大きさですか
I will show you an indicator
インジケーターをお見せします
In 2011, a
2011 年に、
A Great Earthquake Off the Northeast Sea
東北沖大地震
long-standing
長年の
It was the strongest earthquake of its kind ever recorded in Japan
それは日本でこれまでに記録されたこの種の地震としては最大のものでした
Bring to our earth and Japan
私たちの地球と日本に
very serious injury
非常に重傷
The energy released by the earthquake
地震によって放出されたエネルギー
About 10-18 power glue ear
約10-18パワーグルーイヤー
So such a unit is 1000 times its
したがって、そのような単位はその 1000 倍です
so you can know say
だからあなたは言うことができます
This is a very amazing surface energy
これは非常に驚くべき表面エネルギーです
We are now from 1970
私たちは今、1970年から来ています
There is a more accurate measurement of this
これについてはより正確な測定値があります
We express the result of our cool color in terms of heat energy
涼しげな色の結果を熱エネルギーで表現します
we see a result
結果が見えてきました
From 1970 until now
1970年から現在まで
The amount of heat we accumulate on the surface is actually very, very amazing
私たちが表面に蓄積する熱の量は実際には非常に驚くべきものです
Where are these heats born?
この熱はどこで生まれるのでしょうか？
born in our ocean
私たちの海で生まれました
So the light blue you see
だからあなたが見る水色は
It is our shallow city sea water
それは私たちの浅い都市の海水です
The deep blue is the sea water of Shencheng
深い青色は深城の海水です
This accounts for about 90%
これが約90％を占めます
Next are the ice cities of the mountains and the polar glaciers
次は山々の氷の都市と極地の氷河です
about 5%
約5%
What's left is the crust
残ったのは地殻です
none of us thought to say
私たちの誰も言いたくなかった
Inside the land we walk every day
私たちが毎日歩いている土地の中
In fact, about 5% of the heat energy is hidden
実は熱エネルギーの約5％が隠されている
is brown
茶色です
The last dark purple is our atmospheric depth
最後の濃い紫は私たちの大気の深さです
Actually very few
実際には非常に少ない
less than 1%
1%未満
But it's us today
でも今日は私たちです
Seeing changes in our weather
天気の変化を見る
Next, I will tell you from a Kone face like this
次はこんな感じでコネ顔からお伝えします
we've been through so many years
私たちは長い年月を経験してきた
We have accumulated so much heat energy on the surface of the earth
私たちは地球の表面に非常に多くの熱エネルギーを蓄積しています
now hiding in our atmosphere
今私たちの大気圏に隠れています
our oceans our crust
私たちの海、私たちの地殻
What kind of impact
どのような影響があるのか
This starts from the base
これは基礎から始まります
What we see is this little
私たちが見ているのはこの小さなものです
very thin this one
これはとても薄いです
But it changed us
でもそれが私たちを変えた
In fact, we are every day today
実際、私たちは今日も毎日です
every year we experience
毎年私たちは経験します
Partyization in the grassroots
草の根での政党化
In terms of the heat energy it accumulates
蓄積される熱エネルギーに関しては
We only see two very obvious results
非常に明らかな結果は 2 つだけです
the first is
一つ目は
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
from the past hundred years
過去百年から
The temperature of our Earth's surface has been rising
私たちの地球の表面の温度は上昇しています
so we can all see our
私たち全員が私たちの姿を見ることができるように
The temperature of the earth's surface is constantly rising
地球の表面の温度は上昇し続けています
the second
二番目
Our seasons can only change
私たちの季節は変わることしかできない
And it changes in the direction of high temperature
そして高温方向に変化します
This picture tells us that
この写真はそれを教えてくれます
This is one of our climate simulation models
これは当社の気候シミュレーション モデルの 1 つです
This model is actually very simple
このモデルは実際には非常にシンプルです
it tells us
それは私たちに伝えます
Changes in our planet's surface temperature
地球の表面温度の変化
actually very interesting
実際とても興味深い
like a standard medium curve
標準的な中程度のカーブのような
The following is the representative temperature distribution
代表的な温度分布は以下の通りです
low temperature four temperature and high temperature
低温4温度と高温
Generally in medium curve
一般的に中程度のカーブで
when the normal distribution
正規分布のとき
The lower part will be less
下の部分は少なくなります
There are not many high temperature parts
高温部分が少ない
mostly room temperature
ほとんど室温
it represents our region
それは私たちの地域を代表しています
represent the length of our seasons
私たちの季節の長さを表します
So for most organisms on Earth
つまり、地球上のほとんどの生物にとって
We should all be at room temperature
みんな室温にいるはずだよ
But when the thermal energy of our surface increases
しかし、私たちの表面の熱エネルギーが増加すると、
This center of gravity curve will shift
この重心曲線は移動します
it is moving to the right
それは右に動いています
when moving to the right
右に移動するとき
You can see that there are two very obvious results
非常に明白な結果が 2 つあることがわかります。
first it moves this way
まずはこのように動きます
The low temperature part becomes less and less
低温部分が少なくなる
It turns out that in this dark blue so-called low-temperature part
この濃い青色のいわゆる低温部分にあることがわかります。
There are so many words we put it into points
言葉がたくさんあるのでポイントにまとめました
Now there is only a little bit left
さて、残りわずかになりました
on the other hand
一方で
The high temperature part is getting more and more scary
高温部分がどんどん怖くなってきます
The high temperature part in the past is
従来の高温部は
Let's integrate it to get the yellow piece
それを統合して黄色の部分を取得しましょう
Now it has become such a big piece
今ではこんなに大きな作品になってしまいました
In more serious cases, the red part appears
さらに深刻な場合は赤い部分が現れます
this is not in the past
これは過去のことではありません
The red part we call record breaking heat
記録的な猛暑と呼ばれる赤い部分
So bring three results
それで 3 つの結果を持ってくる
The first is that cold waves are getting less and less
一つ目は、寒波が少なくなってきていることです。
Although we just passed a
を通過したばかりですが、
The so-called overlord level cold current
いわゆる覇王レベルの寒流
But this is really going to be less and less in the future
でも、これは将来的にはどんどん減っていきます
But there will be more and more hot wolves in summer
でも夏にはもっと熱いオオカミが増えるだろう
And we're going to see record-breaking heat just keep coming
そして記録的な暑さはこれからも続くだろう
That's what we're seeing seasonally
それは季節ごとに見られるものです
Our ten years are changing rapidly
私たちの10年は急速に変化しています
This is what is happening in Taiwan right now
これが今台湾で起きていることだ
The Japanese came to Taiwan from 1897
日本人は1897年から台湾に来ました
Start helping us set up seven observatories
7 つの天文台の設置に協力を始めてください
We have an accurate record of surface observations
私たちは表面観察の正確な記録を持っています
we can see clearly
私たちははっきりと見ることができます
From 1897 until last year 2015
1897年から昨年2015年まで
Our annual average temperature in Taiwan
台湾の年間平均気温
just like the whole world
全世界と同じように
just keeps going up
ただ上がり続けるだけ
In the process of rising
上昇中
We also see that our seasons are changing
季節が変わっていくこともわかります
The most obvious is summer
一番分かりやすいのは夏です
Let's use the average temperature in July as a representative
代表として7月の平均気温を使ってみましょう
You can see this from 1897 to the present
1897年から現在まで見ることができます
The one in the middle is 1950
真ん中が1950年
this time in 1950
今度は1950年
The temperature in Taiwan's summer has turned over in an instant
台湾の夏の気温も一気に逆転
From cool summer to very hot and hot
涼しい夏から猛暑の夏へ
Then we saw another change
その後、別の変化が見られました
is our winter
私たちの冬は
This winter happened in 1980
この冬は1980年の出来事でした
Just now you saw the temperature of our entire surface
たった今、私たちの表面全体の温度を見ましたね
This average temperature every 10 years begins to change like a jumping pill
この平均気温は 10 年ごとに跳躍薬のように変化し始めます。
We can see the temperature of this winter in Taiwan
台湾のこの冬の気温がわかります
We use January as a representative word
1月を代表的な言葉として使っています
It's a drug-like change
それは麻薬のような変化だ
In the past, our winter temperature will be very cold
以前は、冬の気温は非常に寒かったでしょう
like this time we say our temperature is low
今回のように私たちは体温が低いと言っています
It's like the temperature we saw in 1963
1963年に見た気温のようだ
In fact, it has been difficult to appear after 1980
実は1980年以降は出現しにくくなった
Temperatures like this in the past not only often appeared
このような気温は過去に頻繁に発生しただけでなく、
and the time will be very long
そして時間は非常に長くなります
But now we're only two or three days away
でも今はあと2、3日しかない
And it will be less and less
そしてそれはますます少なくなるでしょう
We have really entered a warm winter
本格的に暖かい冬を迎えましたね
Here you can see a few very unique
ここでは非常にユニークなものをいくつか見ることができます
It is about 10,000 to 5,000 years in the past
およそ1万年から5000年前のことです
Our earth will naturally increase by 1 degree
私たちの地球は自然に 1 度上昇します
We are now more than 100 years old and have surpassed
創業100年を超えた今、
In Taiwan
台湾で
Our average temperature is about 1.4 degrees warmer
私たちの平均気温は約 1.4 度高いです
Our 1998 was the warmest day in Taiwan in the past 100 years
1998 年は台湾で過去 100 年間で最も暖かい日でした
But we'll be there soon
でももうすぐ到着します
So the past few years
それでここ数年
we'll see a year that breaks through 1998
1998年を突破する年が来るだろう
Our past hottest summers were 2007 and 2014 were the hottest
過去に最も暑かった夏は 2007 年で、最も暑かったのは 2014 年でした
But in the future we still have new breakthroughs
しかし、将来的にはまだ新たなブレークスルーがあります
so our seasons are changing
だから私たちの季節は変わっていく
To change the distribution of average temperatures we can use for the 12 months of the year
1 年のうち 12 か月に使用できる平均気温の分布を変更するには
Let me give you an example
例を挙げてみましょう
It's 12 months in a year
1年は12ヶ月です
When the Japanese first came to Taiwan
日本人が初めて台湾に来たとき
Our 12-month seasonal distribution looks like this
12 か月の季節分布は次のようになります
That is, January is not the hottest month in July.
つまり、1 月は 7 月の中で最も暑い月ではありません。
Then slowly come down and go back to 12 months
それからゆっくりと下がって12か月に戻ります
We usually use the average monthly temperature of 20 degrees as a threshold
通常、月平均気温 20 度をしきい値として使用します。
We call it winter when it is lower than 20 degrees
20度を下回ると冬と言います
Anything higher than 25 degrees is called summer
25度を超えると夏と呼ばれます
So judging from this indicator
したがって、この指標から判断すると、
You can see the past 12 months
過去12ヶ月分が見れます
January, February and March are all winter
1月、2月、3月はすべて冬です
then this is our spring
それならこれが私たちの春です
this is our fall
これは私たちの秋です
this is our summer
これは私たちの夏です
summer is six seven eight nine
夏は6時78分9時
This line is the 10-year average from 2006 to 2015
この線は 2006 年から 2015 年までの 10 年間の平均です
rising every month
毎月上がっていく
You put this increase rate every month
この増加率を毎月入れます
average it out
平均してみる
It's about our annual average temperature of 1.4 degrees.
これは年間平均気温 1.4 度に相当します。
but you can see clearly
でもはっきりと見えます
It's still our winter
まだ私たちの冬です
only december january february march
12月のみ 1月 2月 3月
Already starting to get into this not-winter range
すでに冬ではない範囲に入り始めています
But our summer is long
でも僕らの夏は長い
Then our summer temperature also increases very fast
そして、夏の気温も急速に上昇します
this is our present
これが私たちのプレゼントです
If we follow what the IPCC told us just now
IPCCが今言ったことに従えば
The temperature ahead of us will continue to increase
これから先の気温はどんどん上がっていきます
According to our current estimate
現在の推定によると
We are in the next less than 90 years
これから90年も経たないうちに
Our temperature in Taiwan will of course increase
台湾の気温ももちろん上がります
3 degrees the change we bring will be more serious
3度、私たちがもたらす変化はより深刻になるでしょう
the change of season
季節の変わり目
Let's use Taipei City as an example
台北市を例に挙げてみましょう
I can tell you why it is not cold in winter
冬が寒くない理由がわかります
How our summers are getting hotter
私たちの夏はますます暑くなっています
not cold in winter
冬は寒くない
The cold measurement of our temperature in Taipei City is very accurate
台北市の寒冷時の気温測定は非常に正確です
Each hour has an observation
各時間ごとに観察があります
we were in 1976
私たちは1976年にいた
Before 1976 to see
1976年以前を見るには
The temperature is less than ten degrees of the facility
施設内の気温は10度未満です
like this time
今回のように
Our temperature in the facility is ten degrees less than the facility
施設内の気温は施設よりも10度低い
almost fully conductive
ほぼ完全に導電性がある
we call cold snap
私たちは寒波と呼んでいます
You see this pair of weather bureaus
このペアの気象局が見えますね
It must have had a continental cold air mass to clean it
それを浄化するために大陸の寒気団があったに違いありません
about thirteen degrees
約13度
Strong Continental Cold Air Mass
強い大陸性寒気団
About eleven degrees, twelve degrees
11度、12度くらい
This is called a strong continental cold air mass
これを強い大陸性寒気団といいます
Ten degrees less than the facility
施設より10度低い
we call it cold
私たちはそれを寒いと呼びます
by cold standards
冷たい基準で
It can be less than the total hours of ten degrees of the facility in a year
年間の施設の合計使用時間は 10 度未満である可能性があります
Before 1976
1976年以前
There are 167 hours in a year
1年は167時間あります
has now slowly declined
今ではゆっくりと減少しています
not slowly falling
ゆっくりと落ちていない
very fast descent
非常に速い降下
From 167 to 2000
167 年から 2000 年まで
Between 1976 and 55 remaining
1976年から残り55年まで
Now only 37 are left
現在37個のみ残っています
How many hours do we have in 2015
2015年は何時間ありますか
is ten degrees less than the facility
施設より10度低いです
Many people are hard to guess
推測するのが難しい人が多い
One hour
一時間
This year has certainly broken through
今年は確実に突破しました
But it won't exceed this number
ただしこの数字を超えることはありません
so you can know say
だからあなたは言うことができます
Our winter is really getting colder
私たちの冬は本当に寒くなってきました
According to this estimate
この見積もりによると
We are around 2030
私たちは2030年頃です
before we can see
私たちが見る前に
It may be 10 degrees in the regional facilities
地域施設では10度になることもあります
But on the other hand, we look at the high temperature
しかしその一方で、高温に注目してみると、
For high temperature, we say that the daily average temperature will be 30 degrees higher than that of the facility
高温の場合、日平均気温は施設の平均気温より30度高くなると言われています。
If the average temperature of your day is 30 degrees
一日の平均気温が30度の場合
It's very hot at noon
お昼はとても暑いです
about 35 degrees
約35度
For such a number of days
このような日数で言えば
Before 1976, Taipei City probably had less than 12 days a year
1976 年以前は、台北市の年間休日はおそらく 12 日未満でした。
That's an average of 11 days
平均は11日です
Later increased to one month
その後1ヶ月に延長
it's a month and a half now
今は1ヶ月半です
How many days have we passed in 2015?
2015年も何日が経ちましたか？
67 days
67日
so you can see it's really increasing
本当に増加していることがわかります
predicting the end of the century
世紀末を予言する
We have 90 consecutive days
連続90日あります
It's very, very hot
とてもとても暑いです
We are not talking about continuous
私たちは継続的なことについて話しているのではありません
We are able to continue as in 2015
2015年も継続することができました
only about 15 days
わずか15日ほど
90 days in a row
90日連続
So this high temperature is for us
だからこの高温は私たちのためのもの
is a very serious threat
非常に深刻な脅威です
We use a 12-month average distribution like this
このような 12 か月の平均分布を使用します
you can take a look
見てみることができます
Our current picture is what you can see
現在の写真がご覧のとおりです
red line
レッドライン
this is what we have
これが私たちが持っているものです
we still have a little bit of winter
冬はまだ少し残っています
Then a short spring and autumn
それから短い春と秋
long summer
長い夏
But in the future, if the temperature is like this
でも今後、このくらいの気温になったら
we assume
私たちは仮定します
Taiwan's monthly temperatures
台湾の月例気温
It will rise by about three degrees this century
今世紀中には約3度上昇するでしょう
it's conservative
それは保守的です
That is to say, the world is rising
つまり世界は上昇している
double that of the past century
前世紀の2倍
Our Taiwan was originally 1.4 degrees
私たちの台湾はもともと1.4度でした
We estimate about three degrees
推定3度程度
For example, call it two
たとえば、それを 2 とします。
You can see the temperature of each month
月ごとの気温がわかります
Its distribution is roughly like this
分布は大体こんな感じです
must be linear
直線的である必要があります
But the result it brings is
しかし、それがもたらす結果は、
First we don't have winter anymore
まず冬はもうない
Because the threshold of winter is here
冬の入り口がここにあるので
the coldest
一番寒い
January with the coldest temperature
最も気温が低い1月
It's all over 20 degrees
すっかり気温も20度を超えてきましたね
but look at our summer
でも私たちの夏を見てください
it's very very amazing
とてもとても素晴らしいです
We probably have almost eight or nine months of summer
おそらく夏は8か月か9か月近くあるでしょう
so there will be no winter vacation
なので冬休みはありません
no winter
冬はない
We only have three months of heat vacation
暑さ休暇は3か月しかない
not only students
学生だけでなく
all people have to let go
すべての人は手放さなければならない
Because in this three-month period
なぜなら、この3ヶ月の間に
it's hard for us to go to work
私たちにとって仕事に行くのは難しいです
we only have night time
私たちには夜しか時間がない
Only then can we go out and do some activities secretly
そうして初めて、私たちはこっそり外に出て活動することができるのです
this is our atmosphere
これが私たちの雰囲気です
It changes the environment of our entire surface
それは私たちの表面全体の環境を変えます
it changes our seasons
それは私たちの季節を変える
Next we look at another
次に別のものを見てみましょう
We except the atmosphere
私たちは雰囲気を除いて
Now the heat energy increases the most is actually in our oceans
現在、熱エネルギーが最も増加しているのは実際に私たちの海です
This ocean it takes us the surface of the earth
この海は私たちを地球の表面に連れて行きます
The people we have accumulated over the past hundred years
百年かけて築き上げた人材
it sucks it all in
それはすべてを吸い込みます
and sucked in a lot
そしてたくさん吸い込まれた
It's actually a buffer
実はバッファなんです
it is a regulator
それはレギュレーターです
It helps so much heat energy accumulated on our planet
地球上に蓄積された多くの熱エネルギーを助けます
sucked it all in
全てを吸い込んだ
From Shallow City to Deep City
浅い都市から深い都市へ
Shencheng is the sea water below 700 meters
神城は標高700メートル以下の海水です
very huge
非常に巨大な
it absorbs so much heat energy
非常に多くの熱エネルギーを吸収します
In fact, its physical, chemical and biological properties
実際、その物理的、化学的、生物学的特性は
everything is changing
すべてが変化している
even more frightening
さらに恐ろしい
The interaction between the ocean and the atmosphere is very strong
海と大気の相互作用は非常に強い
they are like two angry people
彼らは怒っている二人のようだ
Bad tempered people are the same
性格が悪い人も同じです
So the interaction between them
それで彼らの間の相互作用は
become difficult for us to imagine in the past
昔では想像するのが難しくなった
we are more terrible
私たちはもっとひどいです
When the temperature of the ocean and atmosphere increases
海洋温度と大気温度が上昇すると
we saw a terrible phenomenon
私たちは恐ろしい現象を見た
Nice words are now very, very strong
素敵な言葉は今、とてもとても強いです
If there is this on January 9th
1月9日にこれがあれば
I saw that many people came to listen to the speech of Academician Liu Shaozheng.
多くの人が劉少正学者の講演を聞きに来ているのを見ました。
He told us that under climate warming
彼は私たちに、気候温暖化の下では、
Taiwan's rainfall intensity has increased very, very alarmingly
台湾の降雨量は非常に憂慮すべきほど増加している
this is what we are facing now
これが私たちが今直面していることです
Another typhoon has actually surpassed our past imagination
またまた台風がこれまでの想像を超えてきました
this is what we are going through now
これが私たちが今経験していることです
That's what we actually tested
それは私たちが実際にテストしたものです
This is from 1958 until now
これは1958年から現在までです
We can see the amount of heat and cold above our cool gauge world
クールなゲージの世界の上に熱さと寒さの量が見える
This unit is scarier
このユニットのほうが怖い
It is a 10.22 cm release gel
10.22cmのリリースジェルです
It only tells us that red represents sea water at a depth of 2000 meters
赤が深さ2000メートルの海水を表すということだけがわかります。
Black represents the deep sea water from 700 to 2000 meters
黒は700メートルから2000メートルの深層水を表します
So whether it is above the whole boiling water
それで、沸騰したお湯全体の上にあるかどうか
or deep sea water
または海洋深層水
We only see one and its accumulated heat energy is very, very high
私たちが目にするのは 1 つだけですが、その蓄積された熱エネルギーは非常に高いです。
The whole thing is two kilometers deep
全体の深さは2キロメートルです
It's hard for us to imagine in the past
昔の私たちには想像するのが難しい
in such a short time
こんなに短い間に
Its temperature thermal energy increases so much
その温度熱エネルギーは非常に増加します
If we look at the distribution on the surface of the earth
地球表面の分布を見てみると
The red part is from 1959 to 2008
赤い部分は1959年から2008年まで
How much heat energy we have accumulated during this time
この間にどれだけの熱エネルギーが蓄積されたか
The redder it is, the higher the accumulated heat energy will be in terms of temperature indicators
赤ければ濃いほど、温度表示で蓄えた熱エネルギーが高くなります。
Then look at our Taiwan
それから私たちの台湾を見てください
Our Taiwan is in a range where heat energy accumulation is very high
私たちの台湾は熱エネルギーの蓄積が非常に高い地域にあります
Whether it's our east, west, south or north
それが東でも西でも南でも北でも
The accumulation of heat energy is really very amazing
熱エネルギーの蓄積は本当にすごいです
This is what our oceans are going through right now
これが私たちの海が今まさに起きていることです
The ones that can really cool down are of course very limited.
もちろん、本当に冷却できるものは非常に限られています。
The temperature changed by the accumulated heat energy of our ocean is very, very obvious
私たちの海洋に蓄積された熱エネルギーによって温度が変化することは、非常に明白です。
This obviously has a very dire result in the rain
これは明らかに雨の場合には非常に悲惨な結果をもたらします
Why are we getting so much rain now?
なぜ今こんなに雨が降っているのでしょうか？
because we changed the oceans and atmosphere
私たちが海と大気を変えたから
its thermal energy and its temperature
その熱エネルギーと温度
this is our past
これは私たちの過去です
The temperature of our oceans in the past was low
過去の海はもっと冷たかった
The temperature inside our atmosphere is cool
私たちの大気中の温度は低いです
ocean temperature is low
海水温が低い
So its ability to evaporate and shake off water vapor is actually very limited.
そのため、水蒸気を蒸発させて振り払う能力は実際には非常に限られています。
The temperature of our atmosphere is not high
私たちの大気の温度は高くありません
The temperature is not high, the water vapor it can contain is also very limited
温度は高くなく、含まれる水蒸気も非常に限られています
So at that time our rainfall patterns were all moderate
つまり、当時の降雨パターンはすべて穏やかでした
But now everything has changed
しかし今ではすべてが変わってしまった
this is us now
これが今の私たちです
brought
持ってくる
The temperature of our oceans has been accumulating
私たちの海の温度は上昇し続けています
The thermal energy of its surface is constantly rising
その表面の熱エネルギーは絶えず上昇しています
it's been a steady stream
それは安定した流れだった
Send water vapor from the surface of the sea all the way to us
海面から水蒸気を私たちのところまで送ってください。
Then our big part is inside because of the temperature increase
そうすると、温度が上昇したため、私たちの主要な部分が内部にあります
We just said that over the last 150 years
過去150年間にわたってそう言いました
The surface temperature of the atmosphere has increased by one degree
大気の表面温度が1度上昇しました
This one-degree increase would put the inside of our atmosphere
この 1 度の上昇により、私たちの大気圏は内側に位置することになります。
how much water vapor will increase
水蒸気はどれくらい増えるか
If we listened to Academician Liu Shaocheng last time
前回学者の劉少成氏の話を聞いていたら
He told us that the increase in water vapor is about 7%.
水蒸気の増加は約7％だそうです。
This is when we presumably do climate research science
これはおそらく私たちが気候研究科学を行うときです
We probably generally accept the number
私たちはおそらくその番号を一般的に受け入れます
The evaporation of this 7% water vapor
この7%の水蒸気が蒸発すると、
now in our air
今私たちの空気の中に
if so much
そんなに多ければ
How much water does it have?
どれくらいの水が含まれていますか？
Let's use a unit as a metaphor for everyone
単位をみんなの比喩として使おう
This is the Three Gorges Dam
これが三峡ダムです
The Three Gorges Dam is the largest dam on the surface of our planet
三峡ダムは地球上で最大のダムです
artificial dam
人工ダム
Its appearance is about 40 billion tons
その見た目は約400億トン
40 billion tons is the total water consumption of Taiwan in two years
台湾の2年間の総水消費量は400億トン
very amazing
非常に素晴らしいです
it has so much water if it fills it up
満タンにしたら水が多すぎる
so much water
とてもたくさんの水
but we are in the atmosphere
でも私たちは大気圏にいる
because of the increased
増加したため
We increased the amount of water vapor by 7%
水蒸気量を7%増加しました
How many three dams are there?
三つのダムはいくつありますか?
It's hard for many people to imagine
多くの人にとって想像するのは難しい
its more than twenty thousand
それは2万以上です
So now there's so much water vapor
それで今は水蒸気がたくさんあります
They are all flowing around in our Daji City
それらはすべて私たちの大吉市に流れています
it just needs to have the right cover
適切なカバーがあればいいだけです
suitable environment
適切な環境
it will use the way of super heavy rain
超豪雨の道を使うだろう
fell to our surface
私たちの表面に落ちた
So we can all see now
だから私たちはみんな今見ることができます
our surface
私たちの表面
And of course the ocean
そしてもちろん海も
But the surface has the greatest impact on us humans
しかし、私たち人間に最も大きな影響を与えるのは地球の表面です
The intensity of rainfall is increasing rapidly
雨の強さが急速に増している
This is a result of our observation
これは私たちの観察の結果です
this was last september
これは去年の9月のことでした
This is a photo from the Associated Press on September 10
これは9月10日のAP通信からの写真です
This is when Typhoon Ai Tao is on the 9th
台風9号アイタオ発生時です。
This is the week of September 9th in Japan
これは日本の9月9日の週です
This is in the place of Ikeyama in Kinugawa
ここは鬼怒川の池山の地です
This flood situation
今回の洪水状況は
This torrential rain is Japan's past
この豪雨は日本の過去だ
A heavy rain that has never been experienced before
これまでに経験したことのない大雨
you can see these residents
これらの住人を見ることができます
are on its second floor
その2階にあります
waiting for this
これを待っています
go rescue them
彼らを助けに行ってください
Why are they in heavy rain
なぜ大雨が降っているのか
haven't escaped yet
まだ逃げていない
because they don't even think
彼らは考えもしないから
The amount of rain this time will be so strong
今回の雨の量はかなり強いでしょう
And then inflict such a serious injury on them
そして、彼らにそのような重傷を負わせます
this is us today
これが今日の私たちです
every country
すべての国
every environment
あらゆる環境
what happens to us all
私たち全員に何が起こるのか
the heavy rain we had today
今日は大雨が降った
its intensity
その強さ
the shock it brings
それがもたらす衝撃
None of our past experience
私たちの過去の経験は何もありません
conceivable
考えられる
Japan is so advanced in disaster prevention
日本は防災がとても進んでいます
so careful country
とても慎重な国
will encounter this situation
この状況に遭遇するでしょう
the other places are the same
他の場所も同じです
all the same
すべて同じ
Our Taiwan is like this
私たちの台湾はこんな感じです
Exactly from 1901 until last year
ちょうど 1901 年から昨年まで
We saw
私たちは見た
Taiwan's temperature and rainfall
台湾の気温と降水量
A situation in which it interacts with each other
相互に影響し合う状況
The red one is our temperature
赤いのは私たちの温度です
temperature we can see
私たちが見ることができる温度
it's a long record
それは長い記録です
So it is a five-year Huadong average
つまり、これは5年間の花東平均です
what it sees is
それが見ているものは
Our temperature is the same as the whole world
私たちの温度は全世界と同じです
it goes up and down
それは上がったり下がったりします
but it keeps going up
しかしそれは上がり続けます
It's just that it's fun
ただ楽しいだけです
rise it will be leveled
上がる、平準化される
If it rises again, it will be leveled again
また上がったらまた平らになる
This flattening is the ocean
この平らになったところが海だ
Conditioning helps us buffer the consequences of
コンディショニングは、次のような影響を和らげるのに役立ちます。
But rising and leveling
レベリング
In the process of rising and leveling
上昇と平準化の過程で
We see that the relationship between temperature and rainfall
気温と降水量の関係が分かります
it has a wonderful relationship
素晴らしい関係があります
blue is rain
青は雨です
before this warming
この温暖化の前に
before 1950
1950年以前
We see the rainfall in Taiwan
台湾に雨が降っているのがわかります
It's the blue line
青い線です
It is parallel to the temperature
温度と平行です
temperature rises slowly
温度はゆっくりと上昇します
Rainfall is also increasing
雨量も増えてきています
Its ups and downs are actually very gentle
その起伏は実はとても緩やかなのです
The impact it brings is actually very limited.
それがもたらす影響は実際には非常に限定的です。
It does very little harm to us
それは私たちにほとんど害を与えません
But once sold out of 1950
しかし、1950年に一度販売されてしまった
everything has changed
すべてが変わった
we just saw that
私たちはちょうどそれを見ました
seasons in taiwan
台湾の季節
The first thing to change is summer
まず変わるのは夏
Summer has changed since 1950
1950年から夏は変わった
Why did 1950 change
なぜ1950年は変わったのか
since the 1950s
1950年代以来
average temperature around the world
世界中の平均気温
For the first time surpassed our Medieval Nuki's online
初めて中世のヌキのオンラインを超えた
So it brings up is a
それで、それは
very terrible change
非常にひどい変化
Rainfall in Taiwan
台湾の降雨量
all at once from an amble
散歩から一斉に
becomes a
になる
A completely different shape from the past
今までとは全く違う形
We call it like a roller coaster
私たちはそれをジェットコースターのように呼んでいます
From peak to first strand
ピークから最初のストランドまで
From the peak to the trough
山から谷まで
keeps happening repeatedly
繰り返し起こり続ける
every trough
あらゆる谷
That's where you see the green sword head
そこに緑の剣の頭が見えます
That is, our rainfall is relatively low
つまり、降水量は比較的少ないということです
That is, when there is a drought in Taiwan
つまり、台湾で干ばつが起こったとき、
The first drought occurred in the mid-1960s
最初の干ばつは 1960 年代半ばに発生しました
We gave birth to the so-called Shimen Reservoir
いわゆる石門貯水池が誕生しました
The second drought was around the 1980s
二度目の干ばつは1980年代頃でした
Our Bandit Water Reservoir has been flushed out
Bandit の貯水池が洗い流されました
and then the third time
そして3回目
For the fourth time we are now just passing a fifth time
4回目、今5回目を通過したところです
but go back right away
でもすぐに戻ってください
so our drought will recur
だから私たちの干ばつは再発するだろう
It's just that the time is getting shorter
ただ時間は短くなってきている
faster and faster
加速的に
used to be like this
過去に
15 years between the first and the second
1回目と2回目の間は15年
Only 10 years left from the second to the third
第2次から第3次まであと10年しかない
Now we happen once in less than 10 years
今では10年以内に一度しか起こらない
on the other hand
一方で
The intensity of our torrential rain
私たちの豪雨の強さ
is what you see above
上に表示されているものです
It is the location with more rainfall
降水量が多い場所です
has been rising
上昇している
especially after 1980
特に1980年以降
when its temperature rises rapidly
温度が急激に上昇すると
The intensity of our rainfall is suddenly
突然の雨の強さ
bouncing growth
弾むような成長
especially after 1990
特に1990年以降
We see the rainfall in our Taiwan
私たちの台湾に雨が降るのを見る
completely different from the past
昔とは全く違う
in the past
過去に
This has been the case for a hundred years
これが百年も続いている
just tell us one thing
一つだけ教えてください
That is, the higher the temperature in Taiwan
つまり、台湾の気温が高いほど、
The intensity of our rainfall is really increasing
雨の強さが本当に増しています
Because we will have more and more water and gas sinks
なぜなら、水とガスのシンクがますます増えるからです。
It's hurting us more and more
それは私たちをますます傷つけます
But what I want to remind is this part
しかし、私が思い出したいのはこの部分です
Our temperature is now rising rapidly
私たちの気温は今急速に上昇しています
Our 2015 is already the first ever
私たちの 2015 年はすでに史上初の年です
hottest year on earth
地球上で最も暑い年
but it's still growing
しかしそれはまだ成長しています
So we expect to be entering
したがって、参入すると予想されます
The next wave of this upswing
この上昇の次の波
during this rising period
この上昇期に
We also expect this rainfall intensity in our future
今後もこのような降雨強度が予想されます
will further improve
さらに改善します
It's just that we really can't simulate
ただ実際にシミュレーションすることはできない
no way to imagine
想像する方法もない
There is no way to get accurate
正確に知る方法はない
why
なぜ
Because we didn't have such a record in the past
過去にそんな実績がなかったので
Our boundary condition
私たちの境界条件
There is no way for us to have a very accurate
非常に正確な情報を得る方法はありません
But we can learn from the past
しかし、私たちは過去から学ぶことができます
this extremeness of rainfall
この極端な雨量
you can probably imagine
おそらく想像できるでしょう
The impact we face
私たちが直面する影響
This is after Typhoon Heber in 1996
これは 1996 年の台風ヒーバーの後です
We put every time this big typhoon
この大きな台風のたびに入れています
the torrential rain it brings
それがもたらす豪雨
its rainfall intensity
その降雨量の強さ
We take this 1996
これは 1996 年です
If the average value at that time is used as a benchmark
その時点の平均値をベンチマークとする場合
It also affects the area of ​​our Taiwan
それは私たちの台湾の地域にも影響を与えます
This area is a percentage
この面積はパーセンテージです
So this is 20% 40% 60%
つまり、これは 20% 40% 60% です
This is 50%
これは50%です
That is half of Taiwan
それは台湾の半分です
we see one thing
私たちは一つのことを見ます
Now it's not just a typhoon
もう台風だけじゃないよ
It's the blue dot
青い点です
Or the plum rain is the red square
あるいは梅の雨が赤の広場
Its rainfall intensity is increasing rapidly
降雨強度は急速に増加しています
Just like everyone sees this direction
誰もがこの方向を見るように
it has been increasing very fast
非常に急速に増加しています
especially after 2000
特に2000年以降
Several typhoons we saw
いくつかの台風を見ました
like nali in our taipei in 2001
2001年の台北のナリのように
2008 New Lux in Clear Central
2008 ニュー ラックス (クリア セントラル)
Morakot in southern Taiwan in 2009
2009年、台湾南部のモラコット
and Sura 2012 affecting our whole north
そして北部全体に影響を及ぼすSura 2012
It's something we haven't seen before
それは私たちがこれまで見たことのないものです
the intensity of its rainfall
雨の強さ
the area of ​​damage it causes
それが引き起こすダメージの範囲
It's all beyond our imagination
それはすべて私たちの想像を超えています
But as our surface temperature accumulates,
しかし、私たちの表面温度が蓄積すると、
We also expect that it will continue to grow
私たちもこれからも成長していくことが期待されています
In the case of Morakot
モラコットの場合
When the past happened in 2009
2009 年に過去が起こったとき
it's on october 8 october 9 october 10
10月8日、10月9日、10月10日です
three days
三天的時間
In Alishan, the annual rainfall
阿里山の年間降水量は
Take it all down
すべてを取り下げてください
It takes three days a year to bring it down
崩壊するのに1年に3日かかる
we don't have a flood defense system
私たちには洪水防御システムがない
Our row of red silk can withstand
私たちの赤いシルクの列は耐えることができます
But we won't stop here
しかし、私たちはここで止まりません
We will definitely see a typhoon in the future
今後必ず台風が来るでしょう
It will take our year's rainfall
私たちの年の降雨量が必要になります
It took about two days or one day to bring it down.
倒すのに2日か1日くらいかかりました。
no matter where
どこでも
it's hard for us to bear
私たちにとって耐えるのは難しい
it's raining
雨が降っている
Next, let me tell you about the typhoon
次に、台風についてお話します。
In 2015, we actually had a lot of typhoons
2015年は本当に台風が多かったですね
We average about 25 to 26 a year
年間平均25～26人くらいです
27 in 2015
27年（2015年）
2014 is of course okay
2014年ももちろん大丈夫です
2014 was relatively average
2014 年は比較的平均的でした
31 in 2013
2013年に31人
no matter what
何があっても
When the temperature of sea water is getting higher and higher
海水の温度がどんどん上がってくると、
It is conducive to the formation of typhoons
台風が発生しやすくなる
because of the typhoon
台風のせいで
It has a fundamental constraint
根本的な制約がある
The temperature of the sea water must be set above 28 degrees
海水温度は28度以上に設定する必要があります
But now we set it above 28 degrees
でも今は28度以上に設定してます
The Influence of Southernization of Octave English
オクターブ英語の南方化の影響
Its scope of influence is very wide
その影響範囲は非常に広いです
and from every month
そして毎月から
Every year from January to December
毎年1月から12月まで
like 2015
2015年のように
Typhoons can form every month
台風は毎月発生する可能性があります
this typhoon
この台風
Take 2015 as an example
2015 年を例に挙げると
it tells us
それは私たちに伝えます
what might die in our future
私たちの将来に何が死ぬか
the first number
最初の数以上
Of course, 27 is a lot.
確かに27は多いですね。
The second one is widely distributed
2番目は広く配布されています
You can see this is the southern sea of ​​Japan
ここが日本の南の海だということがわかります
some typhoons form
いくつかの台風が発生する
just to the south of it
そのすぐ南にある
A place higher than our Taiwan
私たちの台湾よりも高い場所
represents the temperature of seawater
海水の温度を表します
This place is already reachable
この場所はすでに到達可能です
It is the threshold of the Shenzhen typhoon
深セン台風の入り口です
And its strength can be very high
そしてその強度は非常に高いものになる可能性があります
2015 was good for the Western Pacific
2015 年は西太平洋にとって良い年でした
But for the Eastern Pacific
しかし東太平洋に関しては
is a very good example
とても良い例です
This is us from 2015
これが2015年の私たちです
compared with past averages
過去の平均と比較して
Brown is average
ブラウンは平均的
Typhoons that should come every month
毎月来るはずの台風
2015 is gray
2015年は灰色
You can see that each month has
それぞれの月にあることがわかります
Except for two months that are relatively low
比較的少ない2か月を除く
These two months are relatively low
この 2 か月は比較的短いです
Every other month exceeds past average sub
隔月で過去の平均サブスクリプションを上回ります
This is one that tells us
これは私たちに告げるものです
The typhoon is really different from the past
台風は昔と全然違う
There is another one because of this warm
この暖かさでもう一つあります
You can see that this is the distribution of sea temperature around the world
これは世界中の海水温の分布であることがわかります
The redder the color, the higher its temperature
色が赤くなるほど温度が高くなります
We can see that this is on August 24th
これは8月24日であることがわかります
From this observation from the satellite
この衛星からの観測から
It can be seen that there are seven at the same time
同時に7つあることがわかります
The seventh can be formed in both the Pacific Ocean and the Atlantic Ocean
7番目は太平洋と大西洋の両方で形成される可能性があります
In the past we can see two
過去には2つ見られました
can see three
3つ見えます
It's not easy to see four
4つ見るのは簡単じゃない
But this time we can see seven
でも今回は7つ見えます
what does this mean
これは何を意味するのでしょうか
represents the warming of our oceans now
現在の海洋の温暖化を表しています
The conditions for forming our typhoon have changed
台風の発生条件が変わった
not only change
変化するだけではなく
It also brings some challenges that we could not have imagined in the past
過去には想像できなかったいくつかの課題ももたらします
For example, on October 23 last year
たとえば、昨年の10月23日
In this America is the east side of the Pacific Ocean
このアメリカは太平洋の東側です
There's a typhoon near this place in Mexico
メキシコのこの近くで台風が来ています
Called Patricksonia
パトリソニアと呼ばれる
as it approaches mexico on october 23
10月23日にメキシコに近づく
This photo was taken is what everyone sees now
撮影されたこの写真は今誰もが見ているものです
We estimate from the MSI and the observed instruments
MSIと観測された機器から推定します
Its wind speed can reach 325 kilometers an hour
その風速は時速325キロメートルに達することもある
Can you imagine that we can observe a typhoon
台風を観測できると想像できますか？
Each hour can reach 325 kilometers
1時間あたりの距離は325キロメートルに達することもある
In November 2013
2013 年 11 月
There is a typhoon called Haiyan
ハイエンという台風が来ています
His relatives in the Philippines
フィリピンにいる彼の親戚
We are already called Mount Tai
私たちはすでに泰山と呼ばれています
Its wind speed is only up to 315 kilometers
風速は最大315キロメートルに過ぎない
This is a typhoon that we have never seen before
これまでに見たことのない台風です
Its wind speed can reach so high
その風速は非常に高くなります
A wind speed like this
このくらいの風速
how do we describe it
それをどう説明すればよいでしょうか
We can use a tornado as an example
例として竜巻を使用してみましょう
Here's the U.S. Tornado Scale
これが米国の竜巻スケールです
Its side represents its wind speed
側面は風速を表します
how many kilometers per hour
時速何キロ
The weakest tornado is our moderate typhoon
最も弱い竜巻は中程度の台風です
Its wind speed is about 105-137 every hour
風速は毎時約 105 ～ 137 です。
It is our moderate typhoon in Taiwan that reaches this
これに到達するのは台湾の穏やかな台風です
Moderate typhoon from middle to this middle speed
中速～中速程度の台風
The strongest we call the disastrous tornado
最も強力なものを悲惨な竜巻と呼びます
Its small wind speed is about 322
小さな風速は約322です
this is very difficult to happen
これは非常に起こりにくいことです
And the impact is terrible
そしてその衝撃もすごい
But it's a tornado
でもそれは竜巻です
What is the extent of the tornado?
竜巻の規模はどの程度ですか?
about 2 kilometers
約2キロ
The wind speed of our typhoon is stronger than this
私たちの台風の風速はこれより強いです
It's the equivalent of a catastrophic tornado
それは壊滅的な竜巻に等しい
But its range is more than 150 kilometers
しかしその射程は150キロ以上
so you can hardly imagine
だからほとんど想像できない
We can actually accumulate energy to a point now
実際にエネルギーをある程度まで蓄積できるようになりました
The typhoon it caused was like a catastrophic tornado
引き起こした台風は壊滅的な竜巻のようだった
it cleans any country anywhere
それはどこの国でもどこでも掃除します
we really can't stop
私たちは本当にやめられない
This is how our oceans are warming
私たちの海はこうして温暖化している
A difficulty we are facing now
私たちが今直面している困難
You can see we changed our atmosphere
雰囲気が変わったのがわかりますね
our seasons have changed
私たちの季節は変わりました
we changed our oceans
私たちは海を変えました
our torrential rain
私たちの豪雨
our typhoon
私たちの台風
Now the form is completely different from the past
今は昔と形が全く違います
what do we see next
次に何が見えるでしょうか
We changed our crust again
もう一度クラストを変更しました
The energy of our crust is constantly accumulating
私たちの地殻のエネルギーは蓄積されています
This continual accumulation has two unfortunate consequences
この継続的な蓄積は 2 つの残念な結果をもたらします
First
初め
The moisture content of our soil is decreasing rapidly
私たちの土壌の水分含有量は急速に減少しています
Our drought is getting worse all over the world
干ばつは世界中で悪化しています
another one
もう一つ
Our Keeneng energy accumulates rapidly
私たちのKeenengエネルギーは急速に蓄積されます
has affected the physical properties of our crust
私たちの地殻の物理的特性に影響を与えている
This is more far-reaching
これはより広範囲に及ぶ
This is the temperature we actually measured
実際に測定した温度です
This is the temperature inside the atmosphere
これは大気中の温度です
From 900 A.D. to the present
西暦 900 年から現在まで
From historical data, we can observe
過去のデータから次のことがわかります。
But we only see one fact
しかし、私たちが目にした事実は一つだけです
We are now from 1900 onwards
今は1900年以降です
Our temperature keeps rising
私たちの体温は上昇し続けています
beyond the past
過去を超えて
A journal recently said
最近ある雑誌でこう言われました
Our earth should be entering the next ice age
私たちの地球は次の氷河期に入るはずです
But because of our human interference
しかし、私たちの人間の介入のせいで、
It's impossible for us to go back to the ice age now
今さら氷河期に戻るのは不可能だ
Our temperature can no longer drop
私たちの体温はもう下がらない
We've now reversed up
今は逆転したよ
And this rise
そしてこの上昇
It will make the next ice age tens of thousands of years later
次の氷河期は数万年後になる
will come back
戻ってきます
Not only does it change the temperature of our atmosphere
大気の温度を変えるだけではありません
The temperature under our ground now
今の地下の温度
Just see the light blue one
水色のものを見てください
Its temperature is also rising rapidly
気温も急激に上昇中
And it's very similar to the temperature of our atmosphere
そしてそれは大気の温度と非常に似ています
not only us
私たちだけではありません
air temperature increases
気温が上昇する
The temperature of the soil in our atmosphere
私たちの大気中の土壌の温度
is also rising
も上昇しています
When the temperature of the soil rises
土の温度が上がると
it had an unfortunate result
残念な結果になりました
Its evaporation is constantly increasing
蒸発量は絶えず増加しています
Once our things are heated
材料が加熱されたら
we can see our water
私たちの水が見える
will leave from the hot place
暑い場所から離れます
and then into a cold location
そして寒い場所へ
Therefore, the water vapor in our soil has been continuously reduced.
したがって、土壌中の水蒸気は減少し続けています。
all the way from our soil to our surface
土壌から地表までずっと
But to reach the surface is to enter our atmosphere
しかし、地表に到達するということは、大気圏に入るということです
it also gets very hot
とても暑くなります
because the atmosphere is warming
雰囲気が暖かくなってきたので
So it starts from a low position on the surface
なので水面の低い位置からスタートします
just move to a higher position
より高い位置に移動するだけ
simply put
簡単に言えば
It's like we took a pump
まるでポンプを手に入れたようだ
keep sucking
吸い続ける
take the moisture of the soil inside our crust
私たちの地殻内の土壌の水分を奪う
all the way down into the soil into our atmosphere
土壌中から大気中までずっと
Then put it in a higher place
じゃあ高いところに置いてね
The result is the blue dot you see
その結果、表示される青い点が表示されます。
is the moisture in the soil
土壌中の水分です
is constantly decreasing
常に減少しています
This is what we are observing now
これが私たちが今観察していることです
this was last november
これは去年の11月でした
We use satellites to see global earth
私たちは衛星を使って地球を観察します
Because of the moisture content in the water and soil
水や土には水分が含まれているため、
The darker the color, the more coffee it represents
色が濃いほど、より多くのコーヒーを表します
It has very little moisture and is in the arid category
水分がほとんどなく、乾燥地帯に属します。
As you can see North America is fine
ご覧のとおり北米は大丈夫です
South America is very serious Southern Africa
南アメリカは非常に深刻な南部アフリカです
Then the Middle East, Eastern Europe, Indian Red Continent
それから中東、東ヨーロッパ、インドの赤い大陸
Indochina Peninsula, Australia and the northern part of mainland China
インドシナ半島、オーストラリア、中国本土北部
Like this every month there is one
こんな感じで毎月あるよ
if you take a look
見てみたら
About half of the world's land
世界の陸地の約半分
Now our soil moisture is seriously insufficient
現在、土壌水分が深刻に不足しています
What does it affect? ​​It affects the production of our agriculture.
それは何に影響しますか? それは私たちの農業生産に影響を与えます。
Therefore, as the southernization continues to lead forward
したがって、南方化が進むにつれ、
its temperature keeps increasing
その温度は上昇し続けています
We only see one unfortunate outcome
残念な結果は 1 つしかありません
The moisture content of our soil is getting lower and lower
私たちの土壌の水分含量はますます低下しています
our future agricultural production
私たちの将来の農業生産
it will be affected very, very badly
非常に深刻な影響を受けるだろう
The other is our current earth science
もう一つは、現在の地球科学です。
a subject of very lively debate
非常に活発な議論の対象
Now when every international conference is held
国際会議が開かれるたびに
We all have a Session that usually provides say
私たちは皆、通常、次のようなセッションを行っています。
What now
今、何
its energy accumulates in our crust
そのエネルギーは私たちの地殻に蓄積されます
to our earth
私たちの地球へ
What kind of impact does its geophysical action bring
その地球物理学的作用はどのような影響をもたらすのか
we are now on science
私たちは今科学を研究しています
are arguing we have no conclusions
結論は出ていないと主張している
we only have different opinions
私たちは異なる意見しか持っていない
One of the views I introduced here
今回ご紹介した景色のひとつ
That is, when the warming
つまり、温暖化が進むと、
When the heat energy is continuously accumulated and continuously increased
熱エネルギーが蓄積され続け、増加し続ける場合
it stimulates our crust
それは私たちの地殻を刺激します
plate-to-plate interaction
プレート間の相互作用
Because the plates are expanding
プレートが広がっているので
So you too swell and I swell too
だからあなたも膨らむ、そして私も膨らむ
The friction between them will increase
両者の間の摩擦は増大するだろう
plate when it's all expanding
全てが拡張した状態のプレート
When the interaction between them increases
二人の交流が増えると
it has two unfortunate consequences
それは2つの残念な結果をもたらします
One is that it squeezes stronger
一つは締め付けが強いこと
Second, when it exceeds the limit it can bear
第二に、耐えられる限界を超えたとき
It will use volcanic eruptions or earthquakes
火山の噴火や地震を利用する
This way to express this energy
このエネルギーをこのように表現する
So as the crust becomes more and more active
地殻がますます活発になるにつれて、
We predict more and more earthquakes
私たちはますます多くの地震を予測します
Volcanoes will become more frequent
火山はもっと頻繁になるだろう
At the same time it will grow in size
同時にサイズも大きくなります
so for now
だから今のところ
it's all a hypothesis
それはすべて仮説です
we are still verifying
まだ検証中です
But in the verification process
しかし検証の過程で
we'll look at past records
過去の記録を見てみます
And past records tell us that
過去の記録はそれを物語っています
things to worry about
心配なこと
actually happening
実際に起こっている
That earthquake is for us in Taiwan
あの地震は台湾の私たちのためのものです
Actually very very important
実はとてもとても大事なこと
because it hurts us a lot
それは私たちをとても傷つけるからです
We in Taiwan have been working hard
台湾の私たちも頑張ってます
Find a way to do so-called earthquake prediction
いわゆる地震予知を行う方法を見つける
This is what our earth is
これが私たちの地球です
One third of our colleagues
私たちの同僚の 3 分の 1 は
a job to try to do
やろうとする仕事
We are all doing earthquake research
みんなで地震の研究をしています
that earthquake prediction
その地震予知
it does four things
それは4つのことを行います
First
初め
when do earthquakes happen
地震はいつ起こりますか
time of occurrence
発生時期
the second
二番目
where it happened
どこでそれが起こったのか
its right place
その正しい場所
how deep is it
どれくらい深いですか
The deeper it is the less it hurts us
それが深ければ深いほど、私たちを傷つけることは少なくなります
The shallower it hurts us the more
浅いほど私たちを傷つける
and this earthquake
そして今回の地震
if it happens
それが起こったら
how big is it
それはどれくらい大きいですか
So we do earthquake prediction
それで地震予知をするのです
Be sure to tell everyone these four things
この4つを必ずみんなに伝えてください
time of earthquake
地震の時
its location
その場所
its depth
その深さ
and its size
そしてそのサイズ
Unfortunately
不幸にも
We have done so many years of research
私たちは長年にわたる研究を行ってきました
I have been studying in the central government for more than 30 years
私は中央政府で30年以上勉強しています
Thirty years
30年
as soon as i entered
入ってすぐに
I started to participate
参加し始めました
Until now we have not broken through
今まで突破できなかった
Now we can't do earthquake prediction right now
今のところ地震予知はできない
Of course we have a little success
もちろん、少しは成功しました
But it's not up to the earthquake prediction
でも地震予知には当てはまらない
We can't tell you these ten things
この10のことはお伝えできません
So earthquake prediction so far
ということで、これまでの地震予知
still an impossible task
まだ不可能な課題です
But although we can't do earthquake prediction
でも地震予知はできないけど
we can do another thing
私たちは別のことができる
risk assessment
リスクアセスメント
Earthquake risk assessment is the same as earthquake prediction
地震リスク評価は地震予知と同じ
Earthquake prediction is a very rigorous scientific research
地震予知は非常に厳密な科学研究です
But the earthquake risk assessment just tells us that
しかし、地震リスク評価は次のことを示しているだけです。
how dangerous is this
これはどのくらい危険ですか
it's like we buy insurance
保険を買うようなものです
100 Cars must be insured
100 車には保険をかけなければなりません
not that you have to crash
クラッシュする必要があるわけではありません
must have a car accident
交通事故に遭うに違いない
But you must buy insurance to prevent
ただし、予防するには保険に加入する必要があります
in case
万一に備えて
your damage will be reduced
あなたのダメージは軽減されます
So we tell you today
そこで今日はお伝えします
In the following I want to tell you
これからお伝えしたいのは、
not earthquake prediction
地震予知ではない
Seismic Risk Assessment
地震リスク評価
It tells us that what we are facing
それは私たちが直面していることを教えてくれます
high risk
リスクが高い
Are we going to make some meaningful preparations?
有意義な準備をするつもりですか？
what kind of test are we going to do
どのようなテストをするつもりですか
First
初め
Is the risk of an earthquake in Taiwan high?
台湾で地震が起こる危険性は高いですか?
The first thing I want to tell you is
まず最初にお伝えしたいことは、
We are in an environment with several companies in one sector
私たちは 1 つの分野に複数の企業が存在する環境にいます
our stakes are high
私たちの賭け金は高い
In 2015 we had several earthquakes
2015年にはいくつかの地震がありました
They are all an environment of several tectonic plates
それらはすべていくつかのプレートの環境です
These are the two major earthquakes that occurred in Nepal on April 25 and May 12, 2015
これらは、2015 年 4 月 25 日と 5 月 12 日にネパールで発生した 2 つの大地震です。
A scale 7.8
スケール7.8
A scale 7.3
スケール7.3
That is an earthquake with a magnitude of 8.3 that occurred off the coast of Chile on September 17
9月17日にチリ沖で発生したマグニチュード8.3の地震です。
It is just two plates
たった二皿ですよ
How far down this plate
このプレートのどこまで
Then an earthquake caused by the rupture of the earth's crust
その後、地殻の破壊による地震が発生
The other one was the massive earthquake that hit the Pakistan-Afghanistan border in October
もう一つは、10月にパキスタンとアフガニスタンの国境を襲った大地震です。
This is a few plates
これは数皿です
An unfortunate result of the Indian Ocean plate and the Eurasian plate
インド洋プレートとユーラシアプレートの不幸な結果
Taiwan is
台湾は
We are a Eurasian plate and the Philippine Sea plate
私たちはユーラシアプレートとフィリピン海プレートです
An environment created by several companies on the Eurasian continental plate
ユーラシア大陸プレート上に複数の企業が作った環境
our bluefish to this
私たちの青魚はこれに
Due to the relationship between several pressures, Henghu is shortening every year. By how much?
いくつかの圧力の関係により、恒湖の距離は年々短縮されています。
about eight centimeters
約8センチメートル
In terms of the pressure of this place, how much it shortens is about five to six centimeters
この場所の圧力で言うとどれくらい縮むかというと5～6センチくらいです
It's the same here, about five to six centimeters per year
こちらも同様で年間5～6センチ程度です。
So we are constantly pressing and colliding on one plate
つまり、私たちは常に 1 つのプレートに押し付けられ、衝突しているのです
one of
の一つ
In an environment where energy accumulates, so we are the first. We are inherently prone to earthquakes
エネルギーが溜まる環境なので、私たちが一番最初に私たちはもともと地震が起きやすい体質です。
Our risk is high, it's a part of our nature
私たちのリスクは高い、それは私たちの性質の一部です
Second, has the warming around us brought some impact to us?
第二に、私たちの周囲の温暖化は私たちに何らかの影響をもたらしましたか?
It seems to be evolving in this direction
この方向に進化してる気がする
This is an article in the geophysics newsletter
これは地球物理ニュースレターの記事です
This is an interesting article from 2014
これは 2014 年の興味深い記事です
He put all earthquakes with a magnitude greater than seven or more from 1979 until March 2014
彼は、1979 年から 2014 年 3 月までのマグニチュード 7 を超えるすべての地震を次のように分類しました。
He lists him all and calculates his frequency and he can see it
彼はすべてをリストアップし、彼の頻度を計算すると、それがわかります
In the past, the frequency was about ten times a year, and then it increased to 12 times, and now it is about 17 times a year.
以前は年10回程度だったのが12回、現在は年17回程度となっています。
about
左右
so its frequency is changing
だからその周波数は変化している
and more and more
そしてますます
faster and faster
加速的に
It's just that it can happen a lot in a year
一年のうちにたくさんのことが起こる可能性があるということです
and its size
そしてそのサイズ
scale seven one scale eight its energy is to participate
スケール 7 1 スケール 8 そのエネルギーは参加することです
32 times the difference
32倍の差
32 times over here
ここでは32回
So the difference between July 1 and September is 900
つまり、7月1日と9月の差は900です
That is, the frequency is 1000 times
つまり、周波数は1000回です
so you can watch this too
だからあなたもこれを見ることができます
Its energy is actually increasing
そのエネルギーは実際に増加しています
So we observe from this actual data
この実際のデータから観察します
I have also seen the past few decades
私も過去数十年を見てきました
The scale at which our major earthquakes occur
大地震が発生する規模
And its frequency is increasing
そしてその頻度は増加しています
Let's use another number
別の番号を使用しましょう
This is the US Geological Survey
これは米国地質調査所です
It puts this all right globally
これで世界的には大丈夫です
It has the scale of what happens on the Global Seismic Network
それは地球規模の地震ネットワークで起こっていることと同じ規模です
put it in place
それを所定の位置に置きます
its size lists it
そのサイズはそれを示しています
We have had this complete report since 1973
私たちは 1973 年以来、この完全な報告書を作成してきました。
We take this data and throw it away
私たちはこのデータを取り出して捨てます
we can also see
私たちも見ることができます
Since 1990
1990年以降
The number of times this major earthquake occurred in the world
この大地震が世界で起きた回数
is indeed increasing
確かに増えています
and increasing very fast
そして非常に急速に増加しています
The average year is about this position
例年はこのくらいの位置です
that's ten times that's fifteen times
それは10倍です それは15倍です
so about eleven times
だから11回くらい
Now it's about sixteen times a year
今では年に16回くらいです
It is actually similar to the study we saw just now.
これは実際、今見た研究と似ています。
But the last few years have been different
しかしここ数年は違います
this is 2010
これは2010年です
You can see that it has been more than 20 times until now
これまで20回以上続いていることがわかります
This is a rare thing in the past
これは昔では珍しいことです
But it's all happened now
しかし、それはすべて今起こったことです
he told us
彼は私たちに語りました
Yes, the conditions of our background are actually changing
はい、私たちの背景の状況は実際に変化しています
We now have more large earthquakes and they are relatively strong.
現在、大きな地震が増えており、比較的強い地震です。
So this is the second factor
これが 2 番目の要素です
Tell us our risks are not small
私たちのリスクは小さくないと教えてください
The third is our own Taiwan
3番目は私たちの台湾です
Of course we in Taiwan have very few
もちろん台湾にはほとんどありません
You have seen earthquakes with a magnitude of seven or more
誰もがマグニチュード7以上の地震を見たことがあります。
We usually scale 3, 4, 5
通常、スケールは 3、4、5 です。
scale 6 we'll have some disasters
スケール6では、いくつかの災害が起こるでしょう
Scale 7 usually only happens once every 30 years
スケール 7 は通常 30 年に 1 回しか発生しません
But now even if it's a felt earthquake
でも今はたとえそれが有感地震だとしても
These earthquakes are about magnitude 3 or above
これらの地震はおよそマグニチュード3以上です
The number of times every year is also different from the past
毎年の回数も昔とは違います
This was before the 1999 Jiji earthquake
これは1999年の時事地震の前のことだった
The average number of felt low earthquakes in a year is about 58
有感低地震の年間平均回数は約58回
So you can see that it's probably like this
そうすると、おそらく次のようになることがわかります
just 100 times
たった100回
it's probably in this place
おそらくこの場所にあります
Its line has been deformed a bit
ラインが少し変形してます
From 1999 to 2008
1999 年から 2008 年まで
This is the one you see
これがあなたが見ているものです
Its count has risen from 58
その数は58から増加しました
Jump to 407
407にジャンプ
probably in this place
おそらくこの場所に
But since 2009
しかし2009年以降は
You can see this one
これを見ればわかります
until the previous year
前年までは
what is its average
その平均はどれくらいですか
more than 600
600以上
So it's obvious
それは明らかです
That's how it has been for more than 20 years
20年以上もそうなんだよ
We can see the low earthquake in Taiwan
台湾で低い地震が見られます
It's just that the frequency of low vibrations has increased.
ただ低振動の周波数が多くなるだけです
it shakes low every time
毎回低く揺れる
In fact, it is a release of energy
実際、それはエネルギーの放出です
This means that the energy we can release
つまり、私たちが解放できるエネルギーは、
growing bigger and bigger
どんどん大きくなる
It also means that our crust
それはまた、私たちの地殻が
In fact, the accumulated energy
実は蓄積されたエネルギーは
Also through these low vibrations to express
また、この低い振動を通して表現するのは、
It's just that the more energy accumulated
ただエネルギーが溜まれば溜まるほど
The number of times this low vibration will be expressed in the future
この低振動が今後何回表現されるか
The scale will be larger
スケールも大きくなるし
So this is the third risk we have
これが私たちが抱えている 3 番目のリスクです
Actually it's not too small
実際は小さすぎません
what is the fourth
4番目は何ですか
The fourth is that we have some relations with Japan
4つ目は、日本と何らかの関係があることです。
This is our plate distribution in the western Pacific
これは西太平洋のプレート分布です
This is the Philippine Sea Plate
これがフィリピン海プレートです
This is the Eurasian plate
これがユーラシアプレートです
this is our taiwan
ここは私たちの台湾です
this is japan this is philippines
ここは日本、ここはフィリピン
Four or three of our countries are in the Western Pacific
私たちの国のうち4つか3つが西太平洋にあります
And both are affected by the extrusion of these two plates
そして両方ともこれら 2 つのプレートの押し出しの影響を受けます
This is the Philippine Sea plate squeezing Eurasia
これはユーラシアを圧迫するフィリピン海プレートです
We got Taiwan up
私たちは台湾を立ち上がらせた
Japan is like us
日本も我々と同じだ
Philippine Sea plate
フィリピン海プレート
Eurasian continental plate
ユーラシア大陸プレートがあります
but more complicated than us
しかし私たちよりも複雑です
It also has the Pacific sea plate and the North American continental plate
太平洋プレートと北米大陸プレートもあります
So it's four plates pressed together
4枚のプレートを押し合わせたものです
So the earthquake in Japan is stronger than ours
つまり、日本の地震は私たちの地震よりも強いのです
It does more damage than us
私たちよりも大きなダメージを与えます
about ten times as much as ours
私たちの約10倍
We look at the past century
過去1世紀を振り返る
There are four earthquakes in Japan that are somewhat related to us
日本には私たちと何らかの関係がある地震が4つあります。
Which four earthquakes came
4 つの地震が来たのはどれですか
The first is the 1896 earthquake we call Sanriku
一つ目は1896年の三陸地震です。
It occurs at the boundary of these two plates
この2つのプレートの境界で発生します
It's very strong with 8.5 on the scale
スケール8.5で非常に強いです
More than 20,000 people died
2万人以上が亡くなった
The second happened in 1923
2回目は1923年に起こった
What happened in the Kanto region is called
関東地方で起きたことはこう呼ばれています
Great Kanto Earthquake
関東大震災
It has a scale of 7.9
スケールは7.9です
It killed more than 140,000 people
14万人以上が死亡した
Because of the fire in winter
冬は火事のせいで
The third is 1995
3回目は1995年
happened in this place
この場所で起こった
A magnitude 7.3 earthquake
マグニチュード7.3の地震
More than 6,000 people died
6,000人以上が死亡
just a bit behind the plate
お皿の少し後ろに
The fourth is 2011
4回目は2011年です
Happened off the coast of Tohoku, Japan
日本の東北沖で起きた
The so-called Great Tohoku Offshore Earthquake
いわゆる東北地方太平洋沖地震
scale 9
スケール9
More than 27,000 people died
27,000人以上が死亡
also caused sea cliffs and
海食崖も引き起こし、
this death at national power plant
国営発電所でのこの死亡事故
compound disaster
複合災害
These four earthquakes
この４つの地震は
What is its relationship with Taiwan?
台湾との関係は何ですか？
We can use this graph to represent
このグラフを使用して次のことを表現できます。
This is from 1900
これは1900年のものです
Earthquakes all over the world
世界中で地震が起きる
This is on a scale over 7.5
これは 7.5 を超えるスケールです
It will be more and more densely distributed
ますます密集していきます
Then the scale is getting stronger and stronger
それからスケールはますます強くなります
We just talked about the three earthquakes
先ほど三つの地震について話しました。
In terms of this time series
今回の時系列で言うと
1896,1923,1995
１８９６、１９２３、１９９５
These are the three earthquakes in Japan
これが日本の３つの地震です
What is the relationship between these three earthquakes and our Taiwan?
この３つの地震と私たちの台湾にはどのような関係があるのでしょうか？
Because just these earthquakes
だって、今回の地震だけは
when these earthquakes
これらの地震のとき
Then it happened in Taiwan
そして台湾でも事件が起きた
large earthquake
大地震
And the death toll is more than 1000 people
そして死者数は1000人以上
We just saw that Japan is full of ten thousand people
日本には一万人が住んでいることが分かりました
we are thousands
私たちは何千人もいます
So we're basically one-tenth of it
基本的には 10 分の 1 です
but for us
しかし私たちにとっては
More than 1,000 people are considered a very serious earthquake
1,000人以上が非常に深刻な地震とみなされる
This is Meishan in 1906
ここは1906年の眉山です
This is the 1935 Hsinchu-Taichung Earthquake
これは 1935 年の新竹・台中地震です
We all remember the 1990s
誰もが 1990 年代を覚えています
GG Earthquake
GG地震
Now it has this earthquake again
今、また地震が起きています
2011 Great Tohoku Offshore Earthquake
2011年東北地方太平洋沖地震
scale is 9
スケールは9です
We see records of past history
過去の歴史の記録を見る
with experience
経験を積んで
Every time there is a major earthquake in Japan
日本で大きな地震が起こるたびに
after a while
しばらくして
we will happen
私たちは起こります
about 10 years like this
このまま約10年
This is about 11 years old
これは約11歳です
This is about 5 years
ここ5年くらいかな
Next we want to say
次に言いたいのは
Now there is another one in Japan
今、日本にももう一つあります
stronger scale
より強力なスケール
a bigger earthquake
もっと大きな地震
Will there be a big earthquake in Taiwan?
台湾で大地震が起きる？
we actually don't know
実際のところはわかりません
Because we can't do earthquake prediction
地震予知はできないから
but we can say
しかし、私たちは言うことができます
we risk a lot
私たちは多くのリスクを冒しています
Because of past experience with this history
このような歴史を持つ過去の経験があるため、
we come now don't ignore
私たちは今来ます、無視しないでください
So now we've told everyone
それで今みんなに伝えました
we have another
私たちにはもう一つあります
from our own environment
私たち自身の環境から
Earthquakes around the world
全世界大地震
This phenomenon of oxidation that occurs
この酸化現象が起こるのが、
our this
私たちのこれ
An increase in earthquakes felt by oneself
自ら感じる地震の増加
Our relationship with Japan
私たちと日本との関係
so when will a big earthquake happen
それで大地震はいつ起こるのでしょう
we do not know
我々は知りません
but you can see
しかし、あなたは見ることができます
about 10 years ago
約10年前
In Japan, it absorbs shock and releases energy
日本では衝撃を吸収しエネルギーを放出する
will be accumulated on our side in Taiwan
そうして初めて、それは台湾の私たちの側に蓄積されるでしょう
Then let's also generate a scale
次に、スケールも生成しましょう
large earthquake
大地震
But this time only 5 years left
でも今回はあと5年しかない
if we say yes
私たちが「はい」と言えば
next big earthquake
次の大地震
5 years too
5年も
follow last time
前回に続いて
this is 2011
これは2011年です
Then our time is actually very very close
それでは、私たちの時代は実際に非常に近づいています
that's pretty much where we are now
それが今のほぼ現状です
so we think
それで私たちは考えます
Our stakes are really high
私たちの賭けは本当に高いです
Because there is such a high risk
リスクが非常に高いので
So we were in April last year
それで私たちは去年の4月に
our center
私たちのセンター
published a policy proposal
政策提案を発表しました
Proposal on the Strategy for the Prevention and Control of Large-Scale Earthquake Disasters
大規模地震災害の予防・制御戦略に関する提言
just saw it and said
ちょうどそれを見て言った
Our Taiwan has recently
私たちの台湾は最近、
As our entire environment changes
私たちの環境全体が変化するにつれて
Our earthquake risk is increasing
地震の危険性が高まっている
We are not saying that there will be a major earthquake
大地震が起こるとは言っていない
But our risk is very high
しかし、私たちのリスクは非常に高いです
like the plane we're on now
私たちが今乗っている飛行機のように
is malaysia airlines
マレーシア航空です
So all our precautions
したがって、私たちのすべての予防策は
Amount of our insurance
弊社の保険金額
will be different from others
他とは違うだろう
So in this policy proposal
そこで今回の政策提言では
we specifically mentioned
私たちは特に言及しました
There are three important policy objectives
重要な政策目標は 3 つあります
I hope to remind the government to work in this direction
政府にこの方向に取り組むよう思い出してもらいたい
The first one, do not open the old house
一つ目は、古い家を開けないこと
The second our lives to ensure
第二に私たちの命を確保するのは
The third function of our society cannot be stopped
私たちの社会の第三の機能を止めることはできない
big earthquake can come
大地震が来るかもしれない
But when the earthquake happened
しかし、地震が起こったとき、
We will definitely be able to make our prevention trails
予防トレイルは必ず作れます
our life assured
私たちの命は保証されています
The functioning of our society is sustainable
私たちの社会は持続可能です
That's what we want the government to work on
それが私たちが政府に取り組んでほしいことです
so this is us
これが私たちです
I hope everyone can also notice
皆さんも気づいていただければ幸いです
that used to be from
それは以前からのものでした
From 1901 to 2015
1901 年から 2015 年まで
There have been earthquakes of this magnitude above six in Taiwan.
台湾ではマグニチュード6を超えるこの地震が発生しています。
if we draw it
それを描けば
It's the drop-down map you see
表示されているのはドロップダウン マップです
All the stars represent scales over six
すべての星は 6 を超えるスケールを表します
It will hurt us a little bit
それは私たちを少し傷つけるでしょう
impact on us
私たちへの影響
must not be ignored
無視してはいけません
it is basically divided into three places
基本的に3つの場所に分かれています
One is our northeast earthquake belt
一つは北東地震帯です
The other one is the Western Seismic Belt
もう一つは西部地震帯です
Another one is the Northeast Earthquake Belt
もう一つは東北地震帯です
then we just said
それから私たちはちょうど言いました
Which of these three earthquake zones is the most dangerous
これら 3 つの地震帯のうち、最も危険なのはどれですか
That's the Western Seismic Belt, of course.
もちろん、それは西部地震帯です。
why
なぜ
Because of these three big earthquakes that we just saw
先ほど起きた三つの大地震のせいで
It is mainly in our western seismic zone
それは主に西部の地震帯にあります
Taichung Miaoli in 1935 This
1935年の台中の苗栗これ
And the miracle of 1999
そして1999年の奇跡
Meishan in 1900
1900年の眉山
They are all in our western seismic zone
それらはすべて私たちの西部地震帯にあります
Because the extrusion of this place is very significant
この場所の押し出しは非常に重要なので、
But it has very few small earthquakes
しかし、小さな地震はほとんどありません
We just saw 600+ oil rod quakes a year
年間600回以上の石油棒地震が発生している
More than three quarters are in our Northeast earthquake zone
4分の3以上が東北地方の地震地帯にある
just let it out
ただ出してください
just knock the energy out of it
そこからエネルギーを取り出すだけです
But the western earthquake zone will be less fat
しかし西部の地震地帯は脂肪が少ないだろう
So this place is still our style
だからこの場所は今でも私たちのスタイルなのです
most severe
最も深刻な
So everyone must not ignore
だからみんな無視してはいけない
There's one more thing we're worried about
もう一つ心配なことがあります
It is the Taipei Metropolitan Area in our Northeast Earthquake Zone
東北地方の地震地帯にある台北都市圏です
You can see we had an earthquake in the past
過去に地震があったことがわかります
But in the past this was 100 years ago
しかし、これは100年前のことです
It is different from our current conditions
今の我々の状況とは違う
There are now more than 6 million people in Taipei City
台北市の人口は現在600万人を超えています
Not only do we now have a large population
今では人口が多いだけではなく、
we have a very important construction
非常に重要な工事があります
our MRT our subway
私たちのMRT 私たちの地下鉄
Our high-speed trains are all underground
私たちの高速鉄道はすべて地下にあります
So if an earthquake occurs in this place
もしここで地震が起きたら
the harm done to us
私たちに与えられた害
Of course you can't ignore
もちろん無視することはできません
In addition to the earthquake on the earthquake road
地震道路上の地震に加えて
If it happened off our northeast coast
もしそれが私たちの北東海岸沖で起こったとしたら
This is the Okinawa Trench
ここが沖縄海溝です
Our southwest coast is the Manila Trench
私たちの南西海岸はマニラ海溝です
It will also have a tsunami formation
津波も発生するだろう
in the qing dynasty
清の時代に
Whether it's Kaohsiung, Tainan or Keelung
高雄でも台南でも基隆でも
There are records of tsunamis
津波の記録もある
just tell us
教えてください
There was an undersea earthquake
海底地震がありました
So if this time it happened in the Northeast Sea too,
ということは、今度は東北海でも起こったら、
There will also be a tsunami risk like Japan
日本のような津波の危険もある
This is something we must never ignore
これは決して無視してはいけないことです
So our northeast coast and our new South China Sea
つまり、私たちの北東海岸と新しい南シナ海
The south coast is where we need to pay special attention
南海岸は特に注意が必要な場所です
this is what we just saw
これが私たちが今見たものです
From the atmosphere to the ocean
大気圏から海洋へ
to our crust
私たちの地殻に
Next, I will add one more
次に、もう一つ追加します
It is the edge of our mountain and the two levels
それは私たちの山の端と2つのレベルです
The white piece of ice dust that you see
君に見える白い氷の粉
Its energy is also accumulating
そのエネルギーも溜まっていく
This accumulation affects us
この積み重ねが私たちに影響を与える
actually very profound
実はとても奥深い
It's actually the same as our crust
それは実際には私たちの地殻と同じです
but its impact on us
しかし、それが私たちに与える影響
It is also what we are about to face
それは私たちがこれから直面しようとしていることでもあります
The first one is in this ice dust
最初のものはこの氷の粉の中にあります
because it melts fast
すぐに溶けるので
It also makes our temperature rise very, very obvious
また、それは私たちの体温を非常に明らかに上昇させます
Its impact is in the two-level region
その影響は 2 レベルの領域にあります
The impact on our world is very, very serious
私たちの世界への影響は非常に深刻です
Even more frightening is that it not only affects the climate
さらに恐ろしいのは、気候に影響を与えるだけではないということです。
Affecting the rise of the north face of the sea
海の北面の隆起に影響を与える
will also affect the stability of our crust in the future
将来の地殻の安定にも影響を与えるだろう
In other words, it will indirectly affect our earthquakes
言い換えれば、間接的に地震に影響を与えることになります。
volcano it's this happening
火山、これが起こっている
This is from 2000 to 2009
これは 2000 年から 2009 年までのことです
We put the whole world where the temperature is rising
世界中の気温が上昇している状況に置きます
make a consolidation
統合を行う
The decade's record
10年間の記録
The warmed place is the reddest and deepest place
温められた場所が一番赤くて深い場所
We can see that there are two places
2か所あることがわかります
One is the Arctic
一つは北極です
One is the Antarctic Peninsula
一つは南極半島です
These two places are our polar regions
この 2 つの場所は私たちの極地です
It heats up not only the fastest
最速で温まるだけではありません
At the same time, it has a great impact on us
同時に私たちにも大きな影響を与えます
What I want to introduce to you today is our Arctic region
今日紹介したいのは北極地域です
Because the Antarctic region basically
基本的には南極地域なので、
It is only limited to the Antarctic Peninsula and the seven continents.
南極半島と7大陸に限定されます。
Other places are pretty good
他の場所はかなり良いです
Our more pressing concern is our Arctic Circle
私たちのより差し迫った懸念は北極圏です
This time the arctic shock
今度は北極ショック
It spread from here
ここから広がった
The warming of the Arctic Circle is currently the largest in the world
北極圏の温暖化は現在世界最大規模
we talked about sea level rise
私たちは海面上昇について話しました
We must mention three
3 つ挙げなければなりません
One is the ice city above our Antarctic continent
一つは南極大陸の上にある氷の都市です
very thick
とても厚い
One is Greenland in the Northern Hemisphere
一つは北半球のグリーンランドです
The roadside above it is also very anti-big
その上の道路脇も非常にアンチビッグです
The third is all our alpine glaciers
3 番目はすべての高山氷河です
But all alpine glaciers
しかし、すべての高山氷河は
you add up all its ice
あなたはその氷をすべて足します
Its volume is 180,000 cubic kilometers
その体積は18万立方キロメートルです
one cubic kilometer
一立方公里
is eleven tons of water
水は11トンです
The effect it can have at our sea level
私たちの海面でそれが及ぼす影響
Actually not high
実は高くない
probably all melted
おそらく全部溶けた
It's only half a meter up
たった0.5メートルの高さだ
This is measured in meters
これはメートル単位で測定されます
we are more worried
私たちはもっと心配です
One is Greenland in the northern hemisphere
一つは北半球のグリーンランドです
it will take us over six meters
6メートル以上かかります
The other is our entire Antarctic continent
もう一つは南極大陸全体です
Antarctica you can see
南極が見える
All add up to more than 70 meters
全部合わせると70メートル以上になる
So those are the two things we're most worried about
つまり、私たちが最も懸念しているのはこれら 2 つです
This piece is what I want today
今日欲しいのはこの作品です
I would like to introduce you to Greenland
グリーンランドを紹介したいと思います
in our northern hemisphere
私たちの北半球では
This is Antarctica
ここは南極です
Antarctica is the fastest-heating continent we have right now
南極大陸は現在地球上で最も急速に加熱している大陸である
This is the Antarctic Peninsula
ここは南極半島です
Then there's West Antarctica
次に西南極です
Because the area of ​​the ice sheet on the West Antarctic Continent melts
西南極大陸の氷床の面積が溶けるため
would raise the sea level by eight meters
海面は8メートル上昇するだろう
But so far its impact
しかし、これまでのところその影響は
Not so fast and obvious
それほど速くなく、明らかではありません
Our biggest concern right now is Greenland
私たちの今の最大の懸念はグリーンランドです
this is greenland
ここはグリーンランドです
this is our arctic ocean
ここは私たちの北極海です
this is our arctic
ここは私たちの北極です
Its impact is actually very, very serious
その影響は実際には非常に深刻です
I just said Arctic
北極って言ったばかりです
If all of this Greenland melts
このグリーンランドがすべて溶けてしまったら
Global sea levels will rise
世界の海面は上昇する
Exceed
超えた
6 meters
6メートル
That is to say, this piece
つまりこの作品は
So what is the biggest impact of this piece?
では、この作品の最大の影響は何でしょうか？
This is the Arctic Ocean
ここは北極海です
Arctic Ocean due to warming
温暖化による北極海
it's gone
なくなってしまった
It melts very, very fast
とてもとても早く溶けます
But the Arctic Ocean is a seashore
しかし、北極海は海岸です
Greenland is the land bank
グリーンランドは土地銀行です
The beach is the water in the glass
ビーチはガラスの中の水です
It melts the water inside the cup does not rise
コップの中の水が溶けて上がらない
But it is a protected plant of Greenland
でもグリーンランドの保護植物です
that is, its moderation
つまり、その節度
Without this Arctic Ocean Greenland
この北極海がなければグリーンランド
The barrier will be lost in an instant
バリアは一瞬で消えてしまう
it will melt quickly
すぐに溶けてしまいます
So the Arctic Ocean is where we do this climate observation
北極海は私たちがこの気候観測を行う場所です
A very important observation indicator
非常に重要な観察指標
I just said this indicator
私はちょうどこの指標を言いました
in 2015
2015年に
it used to be in winter
昔は冬だった
The area of ​​its ice sheet has become very, very small
氷床の面積は非常に小さくなりました
lowest since dominance
支配以来最低
What you can see on the picture is from 1979
写真にあるのは1979年のものです
Until the biggest winter of 2015
2015年の最大の冬まで
This waterfront area we call March
マーチと呼ばれるこのウォーターフロントエリア
It's the youngest time in summer
夏が一番若い時期です
We call the seaside area of ​​september
9月の臨海エリアといいます
A curve of the two changes of seashore area
海岸域の二つの変化の曲線
This is what we just saw
これが私たちが今見たものです
so-called March
いわゆる3月
the biggest winter
最大の冬
Last March was the lowest in this place
昨年の3月はこの場所で最低だった
Why should we worry so much at our lowest?
なぜ私たちはどん底の時にこれほど心配しなければならないのでしょうか？
because in the past
なぜなら昔は
every time its lowest
最低のたびに
The last time it was 2006
前回は2006年でした
this is 2011
これは2011年です
they are very low
彼らはとても低いです
every time it's low
低いたびに
Next we summer every other summer
次は隔夏で夏にします
Its beach area is even lower
ビーチエリアはさらに低い
So you can see in 2006 this is 2007
2006 年が 2007 年であることがわかります。
it's very low
とても低いです
2011 it was 2012
2011年だった、それは2012年だった
what is this now
これは今何ですか
So we predict that by 2016
したがって、2016 年までに
Our summer waterfront area
夏のウォーターフロントエリア
It will probably be lower than this
おそらくこれよりも下がるでしょう
2012 was the lowest
2012年が最低だった
How much of its ice sheet remains in summer
夏にはどれくらいの氷床が残るのか
3.41 million square kilometers
341万平方キロメートル
how much in the past
過去どれくらい
past in this
この中の過去
before
前
In 1980 it was about the same
1980年もほぼ同じだった
7.9 million
790万
Nearly 8 million square kilometers
約800万平方キロメートル
Now there are only about 3 million left
もう300万くらいしか残ってない
Then this year, there will be only about 4 million square kilometers left.
そうなると今年は約400万平方キロメートルしか残らないことになる。
Then next year will be this year
じゃあ来年は今年かな
This is the September we are facing now
これが私たちが今直面している9月です
We estimate that it will be lower than 3.41 million
341万人を下回ると予想しています
follow this trend
この傾向に従う
You don't need this very accurate model like ours
私たちのような非常に正確なモデルは必要ありません
or our simulation to predict
または予測するためのシミュレーション
We just use simple math
単純な計算を使用するだけです
we can all tell
私たち全員が言うことができます
According to the trend like this
このような傾向に応じて
when will we see
いつ見られますか
There is a summer in the Arctic Ocean without soldiers
北極海には兵士のいない夏がある
Of course there will be winter
もちろん冬もありますよ
will summer appear
夏は現れるだろうか
From this estimate
この見積もりから
Probably no more than 2030
おそらく 2030 年まで
We are now in 2016
2016年になりました
So we really don't have much time
だから本当に時間がないんです
When this is before 2030
これが2030年以前だと
the piece we saw
私たちが見た作品
This is called the Arctic Ocean coast
ここは北極海沿岸と呼ばれています
This was in 2012
これは2012年のことでした
Then in the future it will be smaller than this sea
そうすれば将来はこの海よりも小さくなるでしょう
then getting smaller
それから小さくなる
Getting smaller and smaller
どんどん小さくなっていきます
will eventually disappear
やがて消えるだろう
when it disappears
それが消えるとき
will happen
それは起こるだろう
Then I won't talk about other things today.
それでは、今日は他のことについては話しません。
I only talk about this matter
この件についてのみ話します
That's when the Arctic Sun has no ice in the summer
それは、夏に北極の太陽に氷が存在しないときです。
The first to be affected was Greenland
最初に被害を受けたのはグリーンランドだった
Greenland is so thick
グリーンランドはとても厚いです
2.6 million tens of thousands of cubic kilometers of water
260万立方キロメートルの水
will be affected
影響を受けるだろう
It only needs to disappear 1/1
1/1消えればいいだけ
Our global sea level will rise by 60 cm
世界の海面は60センチメートル上昇する
So the sea level will be affected by the arctic sun
つまり海面は北極の太陽の影響を受けることになる
when there is no summer
夏がないとき
will start to speed up the dissolution of Greenland
グリーンランドの解体が加速し始めるだろう
Then the global sea level will rise by leaps and bounds
そうすれば世界の海面は飛躍的に上昇するだろう
This is a problem we are going to face now
これは私たちがこれから直面する問題です
And it's not that long
そして、それはそれほど長くはありません
Following the trend we just looked at
先ほど見てきた傾向に沿って
We'll have to face it before 2030
2030年までに直面しなければならないだろう
This is the IPCC on a seminar
こちらはセミナー中の IPCC です
a data published by it
それによって公開されたデータ
it tells us
それは私たちに伝えます
From 1900 to the present and the future
1900年から現在、そして未来へ
Possible Trends in Our Global Sea Level Rise
世界的な海面上昇の可能性のある傾向
The future is of course blue and this is history
もちろん未来は青、これは歴史だ
This is the one you see
これがあなたが見ているものです
this is 1900
これは1900年です
until 2000
2000年まで
The world has risen in 100 years
世界は100年後に上昇した
this is centimeters
これはセンチメートルです
Rise about 20 cm
股上約20cm
So the average year is 0.2 cm
つまり、平均年は0.2cmです
is 2 kilometers
2キロです
But in the future our sea level
でも将来的には海面が
100 years 200 years 300 years
100年200年300年
Just continue to rise in this way
このまま上昇し続けるだけ
Its inaccuracy is our gray area
その不正確さはグレーゾーンです
but now we all know
しかし今では誰もが知っています
This estimate is too conservative
この見積もりは保守的すぎる
not accurate anymore
もう正確ではない
now we know that
今、私たちはそれを知っています
before 2000
2000年以前
It was originally estimated to be only one meter at most
当初は最大でもわずか1メートルと推定されていました
now we find
今私たちは見つけました
Words go so fast with our environment
言葉は私たちの環境にとても早く溶け込みます
the edge of our two levels
私たちの2つのレベルの端
it disappears so quickly
とても早く消えてしまいます
It has such a big impact
こんなに大きな影響があるのですね
we now know that
私たちは今それを知っています
Probably at least one meter
おそらく少なくとも1メートル
How many more than one meter
1メートル以上は何メートル
we don't really have an answer right now
今のところ答えはありません
we totally want to see
私たちは完全に見たいです
We can slow climate warming in the future
将来的には気候温暖化を遅らせることができる
Then let it happen how slowly you decide
それから、どれだけゆっくりと決めるか、それを実現させましょう
But we are now one meter
でも今は1メートルです
Probably can't escape
たぶん逃げられない
So now I'm going to tell you that it's unfortunate
だから今から言いますが、それは残念なことです
before 2000
2000年以前
we rise below
私たちは下に上がります
one meter
1メートル
How much have we been in the past 100 years
この100年で私たちはどれだけ成長しただろうか
20 cm
20cm
But the next 100 years is one meter
でも次の100年は1メートル
The difference is really, really big
その違いは本当に本当に大きいです
So 21st century sea level
つまり21世紀の海面
rapid rise like this
このような急上昇
Let's face the very terrible
非常に恐ろしいことに直面しましょう
We just said that the 21st century is the century of high temperature
21世紀は高温の世紀だと先ほど言いました
is the century of extreme change in water resources
今世紀は水資源の極端な変化の世紀です
It is our agricultural production that will be impacted
影響を受けるのは私たちの農業生産です
a century of famine
飢餓の世紀
But when the sea level rises
しかし海面が上昇すると
it tells us
それは私たちに伝えます
all the coasts of the world
世界のすべての海岸
Its population is rapidly beginning to migrate
人口は急速に移住し始めている
move to higher places
より高い場所に移動する
So this is a century of great migration
つまり、今世紀は大移動の世紀である
The same is true of our Taiwan
私たちの台湾も同じです
Mainland China has actually been hit very, very hard
中国本土は実際に非常に大きな打撃を受けています
So if we are going to develop in mainland China
中国本土で開発する場合
These are the ones to avoid in particular
これらは特に避けるべきものです
places that will be hit in the future
今後襲われるであろう場所
our taiwan
私たちの台湾
If we use a 3D topographic map to show it
3D地形図で表現してみると
that's it
それでおしまい
The very low place in this picture is the altitude
この写真の一番低いところが標高です
Below 25 meters
25メートル以下
all these dark blue
これらすべての濃い青
then light blue
それから水色
The gray ones are places below 100 meters above sea level
灰色のものは標高100メートル以下の場所です
The yellow ones are places above 100 meters above sea level
黄色は標高100メートル以上の場所
Above 100 meters is
100メートルを超えると、
When Antarctica Melts
南極が溶けるとき
we won't be drowned
私たちは溺れないよ
This is where Taiwan will always be
ここが台湾の永遠の場所です
So Taiwan now we still have these dark blue locations
台湾には今でもこの紺色の場所が残っています
But slowly with warming
でも、温暖化とともにゆっくりと
it will slowly disappear
それはゆっくりと消えていきます
It has a huge impact on us
それは私たちに多大な影響を与えます
You can see that the Lanyang Plain is missing
蘭陽平原が欠けていることがわかります
Our Taipei Basin
私たちの台北盆地
many people don't know
多くの人は知りません
Three-quarters of the area of ​​our Taipei land
台北の土地の面積の4分の3
All below 20 meters
いずれも20メートル以下
Therefore, after the sea plain rises in the future,
したがって、将来海原が隆起した後、
Along this Guandu this love mouth
この官渡に沿ってこの愛の口
it will slowly sink in
ゆっくりと沈んでいきます
our west coast
私たちの西海岸
Especially from the south of Changhua
特に彰化南部から
until our Pingtung
屏東まで
The impact is actually very, very big
その影響は実際には非常に非常に大きいです
In fact, we don't have much time for shadows
実際、影を作る時間はあまりありません
we just said
私たちは今言いました
when this arctic sun it has no ice in summer
この北極の太陽には夏には氷がありません
This phenomenon will start to become more and more serious
この現象はますます深刻になるだろう
Then we don't have much time
それでは時間がありません
We are now so shadowy time
今はとても暗い時代です
only ten years
たった10年
not more than one generation
一世代を超えない
So we really need to go well
だから本当にうまくいく必要がある
face the shadow
影と向き合って
This is our current Taipei local
これが現在の台北ローカルです
This Taipei local is now crowded with more than 6 million people
この台北の地元の街は現在 600 万人以上の人々で賑わっています
We thought we could stay in Taipei for the rest of our lives
私たちは残りの人生を台北に残れると思っていました
We can all develop assets here
ここでは誰もが資産を開発できます
but we were all wrong
でも私たちは皆間違っていた
With this warming
この温暖化に伴い
With our rapidly changing environment
急速に変化する環境に合わせて
We estimate that in the next one or two hundred years, Taipei
今後 100 年か 200 年の間に、台北は
it will start to change rapidly
それは急速に変化し始めるだろう
it will make many of us
それは私たちの多くを作るでしょう
because of sea level rise
海面上昇のせいで
Because the water in it can't drain out
中の水が抜けないので
It began to make it impossible for many people to live here
多くの人がここに住むことが不可能になり始めた
finally have to leave
ついに出発しなければならない
So the locals in Taipei actually started from this
つまり、台北の地元の人たちは実際にこれから始めたのです
For our earth science research
地球科学研究のため
it's actually very dangerous
それは実際にはとても危険です
We have to migrate slowly to higher places
ゆっくりと高いところへ移動しなければなりません
but we don't have much time
でも時間があまりない
More than 6 million people
600万人以上
if you want to migrate it
移行したい場合は
how do you migrate
どうやって移住するの？
in such a short time
こんなに短い間に
in such a limited time
そんな限られた時間の中で
So I put just that
だから私はそれだけを入れました
This picture of IPCC, this energy accumulation
IPCCのこの写真、このエネルギー蓄積
From atmosphere to ocean to crust
大気から海洋、そして地殻まで
until the edge of Gao Shan's two levels
ガオシャンの2つのレベルの端まで
tell everyone
みんなに言ってください
we created an unfortunate environment
私たちは不幸な環境を作ってしまった
we made a terrible crop
私たちはひどい作物を作りました
we hurt our earth
私たちは地球を傷つけます
which in turn affects us
それはひいては私たちに影響を与える
So the twenty-first century is a
したがって、21世紀は
post period extreme change catastrophe life time era
生理後 極端な変化 大惨事 生涯 時代
We are now suffering a consequence of this
私たちは今、その影響に苦しんでいます
This is the German debt insurance company
これはドイツの債務保険会社です
A picture he accumulated and published
彼が集めて公開した写真
He began to report natural disasters all over the world in 1980
彼は 1980 年に世界中の自然災害を報告し始めました。
accumulate it with different scales
さまざまなスケールでそれを蓄積する
We can see that this is the number of times a year
これは年間の回数であることがわかります
Average times over the past year
過去 1 年間の平均タイム
400 times at 200 times
200回で400回
about 300 times
約300回
Then it went up to 500 times
その後500回まで上がった
Then received 700 times
その後700回受信しました
In the past ten years
過去10年間で
It has probably risen to about 900 times
おそらく900倍くらいになったでしょう
Last year, more than 1,000 times
昨年は1,000回以上
so we only see one result
したがって、表示される結果は 1 つだけです
With this global warming
この地球温暖化に伴い、
With the increasing number of natural disasters
自然災害が増える中、
Disasters we face
私たちが直面する災害
In fact, more and more dangerous
実際、ますます危険です
It's hurting us more and more
それは私たちをますます傷つけます
Taiwan is a natural disaster
台湾は自然災害だ
very big place
とても大きな場所
Disasters that 73% of us face
私たちの 73% が直面する災害
three types of natural disasters
3種類の自然災害
90% of us need to face two kinds of natural disasters
私たちの90%は2種類の自然災害に直面する必要があります
But with global warming
しかし、地球温暖化により、
Our ecological environment has been harmed so much
私たちの生態環境は大きく損なわれています
our risk is greater
私たちのリスクの方が大きい
Our challenge is higher
私たちの挑戦はさらに高い
In the knowledge test of the previous month
前月の知識テストで
Director Lin of the Political Institute
林政治研究所所長
gave us the season theory
季節理論を教えてくれました
During the season he talked about two things
シーズン中、彼は2つのことについて話しました
That is to say, suppose there are two people
つまり、二人の人がいるとします。
Both men were caught by the police
二人とも警察に捕まった
if they cooperate
彼らが協力すれば
They will serve the shortest time in prison
彼らは最短の期間で刑務所に服役することになる
They can all get the best result
全員が最高の結果を得ることができます
if they both betray each other
もし二人がお互いを裏切ったら
both of them will be unlucky
二人とも不幸になるだろう
The season theory is not only applied to our politics
季節理論は政治だけに適用されるわけではありません
Applied in many fields of our
当社の多くの分野で応用されています
also applied to our climate change
私たちの気候変動にも適用される
Our Climate Change Now
私たちの気候変動は今
The vice president we just said
先ほど言った副大統領
Just passed the Paris climate negotiations
パリ気候変動交渉が通過したばかり
Climate negotiations is a very important season theory
気候交渉は非常に重要な季節理論です
he told us
彼は私たちに語りました
We must never again harm our environment
私たちは二度と環境に害を与えてはなりません
We can no longer see ourselves like this
私たちはもう自分自身をこのように見ることはできません
two people are the same
二人は同じです
Let's do the biggest damage to each other
お互いに最大のダメージを与えましょう
with torture
拷問付き
we must sacrifice ourselves
私たちは自分自身を犠牲にしなければなりません
We would rather sacrifice ourselves first
私たちはむしろ最初に自分自身を犠牲にします
benefit each other
お互いに利益をもたらす
Although we won't get the biggest
最大のものは得られないとしても
We won't get the maximum number of points ourselves
自分たちで最大ポイントを獲得することはできません
But the result of our joint efforts
しかし、私たちの共同の努力の結果
will make our environment better
私たちの環境をより良くします
this is our climate change
これは私たちの気候変動です
One of the most important of our negotiations
私たちの交渉の中で最も重要なことの一つ
That is to say
つまり
we must first sacrifice ourselves
私たちはまず自分自身を犠牲にしなければなりません
Then complete our overall situation
次に、全体的な状況を完成させます
And perfect our earth our future
そして私たちの地球と私たちの未来を完璧にしましょう
in this case
この場合
All we have to do is two very important things
私たちがしなければならないのは 2 つの非常に重要なことだけです
the whole world has to do
全世界がしなければならないこと
The first must be simple and simple
最初はシンプルでシンプルでなければなりません
is that we just saw all these changes
私たちはこれらすべての変化を目の当たりにしたということです
The first one, its change will be relatively small
1つ目は、その変化は比較的小さいでしょう
it is slower
それは遅いです
It used to be like this
昔はこうだった
now we can slowly
今はゆっくりできるよ
give us more time to deal with
もっと時間をください。
And then let this change make us more bearable
そして、この変化が私たちをもっと耐えられるものにしましょう
But there is another thing I want to remind everyone
しかし、皆さんに思い出していただきたいことがもう一つあります
What cannot be ignored is the housing debt
無視できないのは住宅ローンです
in 101 years
101年後には
The Executive Yuan also announced
行政院も発表
National Climate Change Adaptation Policy Framework
国家気候変動適応政策枠組み
in this program
この番組では
In fact, the two most important points
実は最も重要な2つのポイントは、
One is that we must start reducing energy and carbon
1つは、エネルギーと炭素の削減を始めなければならないということです。
to slow down
ゆっくりする
Second, we must start to make some adjustments
第二に、いくつかの調整を開始する必要があります
The so-called adjustment is what we just said
いわゆる調整というのは今言ったとおりです。
Be sure to start doing housing debt operations
必ず住宅ローン運用を始めましょう
How can we reduce energy and carbon?
どうすればエネルギーと炭素を削減できるでしょうか?
we still need time
まだ時間が必要です
All countries in the world need to work hard to achieve this operation
世界中の国々がこの作戦を達成するために懸命に取り組む必要がある
We are now in 2016
2016年になりました
right here
ここにあります
We emit so much carbon a year
私たちは年間で非常に多くの二酸化炭素を排出します
If we can work together globally
世界中で協力できれば
We're probably headed in this direction
おそらくこの方向に進んでいると思います
We will now line up for a year
これから1年間並びます
The total amount is about 30 billion tons of carbon dioxide
総量は約300億トンの二酸化炭素
but we are willing to do these things
しかし、私たちはこれらのことを喜んで行います
Carbon Pujo Storage Renewable Energy Nuclear Energy
炭素プジョ貯蔵 再生可能エネルギー 原子力
Of course we cannot use nuclear energy in Taiwan
もちろん台湾では原子力は使えない
We replace it with other
他のものと交換します
We increase power generation efficiency
発電効率を高めます
Fuel Switching Energy use replace it
燃料の切り替え エネルギーの使用を置き換える
We even increased our debuff
デバフも増やしました
with our efficiency
私たちの効率性を活かして
we can walk slowly from here
ここからはゆっくり歩いていけます
We hope that by 2050
2050 年までに
The world can drop to 141 tons
世界の重量は141トンまで減少する可能性がある
if we can do this
これができれば
The agricultural soil of our large strata will not break through
私たちの広大な地層の農地土壌は突き破ることはできません
WE JUST SEE THE TERRIBLE THRESHOLD OF 450
450 という恐ろしいしきい値が見えるだけです
but we need 35 years
でも35年は必要だ
In 35 years we tried to do it
35年かけて私たちはそれを実現しようとしました
when we do really well
私たちが本当にうまくいったとき
Maybe we can do that
もしかしたら、次の地点に到達できるかもしれない
But in 35 years
しかし35年後には
The temperature of our atmosphere will increase
私たちの大気の温度は上昇します
our carbon dioxide
私たちの二酸化炭素
People are continuing our accumulation
人々は私たちの蓄積を続けています
what we just saw
私たちが今見たもの
From the atmosphere to the ocean to our subterranean world
大気から海洋、そして地下世界まで
even the two armies
両軍さえも
it condition won't go away
その状態は消えない
Even in terms of Arctic ice
北極の氷に関しても
by this time
今ごろは
We have no ice in summer
夏には氷がありません
so what do we have to suffer
それで私たちは何を苦しまなければならないのですか
And bear with what we just saw
そして今見たことを我慢してください
seasonal changes
季節の変化
Heavy rain, typhoons, even volcanic earthquakes
大雨、台風、さらには火山性地震も
And our sea level is rising rapidly
そして海面は急速に上昇しています
The impact
インパクト
So what I want to tell you today is
そこで今日お伝えしたいことは、
absolutely simple must do
絶対にシンプルでなければならない
But don't ignore
でも無視しないでください
That's what we're going to do now
それがこれからやることです
that we're going to start doing
私たちがこれから始めようとしていること
facing our natural disasters
自然災害に直面する
every year in the future
今後も毎年
We all have to face typhoons, torrential rains, flooding, mountain landslides, high temperature and heat
私たちは皆、台風、集中豪雨、洪水、山の土砂崩れ、高温、暑さに直面しなければなりません。
The cold wave we are facing today is actually a small one
今日私たちが直面している寒波は実際には小さなものです
are local
地元の人です
The real shocks we face are these
私たちが直面する本当のショックはこれです
Also, our recent earthquake risk is very high
また、最近の地震の危険性は非常に高いです
So you must not ignore this one or two years
だからこの1、2年を無視してはいけません
That is, our earthquake risk is very high
つまり、地震の危険性が非常に高いということです
we have to prepare
私たちは準備をしなければなりません
we all hope he doesn't come
私たちは皆、彼が来ないことを願っています
but we don't know if he will come
でも彼が来るかどうかは分かりません
we are not sure
私たちにはわかりません
The only thing we can do is to prepare for earthquakes
私たちにできることは地震に備えることだけ
More importantly, don't ignore
さらに重要なのは、無視しないことです
before 2030
2030年までに
If there is really no ice in Beibinyang
本当に北賓陽に氷がないとしたら
According to this trend
この傾向に従って
It may be difficult for us to recover
回復するのは難しいかもしれない
the sea level will rise faster
海面はもっと早く上昇するだろう
Our bay digs will flood
私たちの湾の掘削地は洪水になるだろう
Increased majesty
威厳の増大
We probably can't escape the large-scale semi-relocation
大規模な準移転は避けられないだろう
So if we are not ready now
それで、今準備ができていない場合は、
the future is too late
未来は遅すぎる
That's what we have to face in the future
それが私たちが将来直面しなければならないことです
How about facing this before?
その前にこれに直面してみてはどうでしょうか？
just tell us
教えてください
We must do self-disaster, disaster prevention, disaster avoidance and disaster prevention
自主災害、防災、災害回避、防災をしなければなりません
I share with you today
今日は皆さんとシェアします
I accumulated all these data
これらすべてのデータを蓄積しました
the main thing is
主なことは
Give everyone a knowledge to build this foundation
この基盤を構築するための知識を全員に提供する
this basic knowledge
この基礎知​​識
It's useless to know
知っても無駄だ
More importantly, I hope everyone can do a good job in disaster prevention
それよりも、皆さんが防災にしっかり取り組んでほしいと願っています
Disaster avoidance and disaster relief work
災害回避・災害救援活動
These jobs are the most important
これらの仕事が最も重要です
that's here today
それは今日ここにあります
when you come in
あなたが入ってくるとき
Our secretary colleagues give everyone
私たちの秘書の同僚は全員に
will send a so-called
いわゆる
Emergency Shelter Kit Manual
緊急避難セットマニュアル
that besides this
これ以外に
In fact, our local government
実は私たちの地方自治体も、
have done some meaningful work
意味のある仕事をしました
Like the Taipei City Government has one
たとえば、台北市政府には次のようなものがあります。
Disaster Prevention Handbook for Citizens
県民のための防災ハンドブック
Many people may have already downloaded
すでにダウンロードされている方も多いかもしれません
if not downloaded
ダウンロードされていない場合
You must go home today
今日は家に帰らなければなりません
I will download this manual
このマニュアルをダウンロードします
He put us when natural disasters happen
自然災害が起こったとき、彼は私たちを助けてくれました
what should we do
私たちは何をすべき
how to prevent
防ぐ方法
put it all in
全部入れて
integrated in
に統合されている
Everyone must take a good look
みんなもよく見てみるといいよ
Then start to prepare for this disaster prevention
さあ、防災の準備を始めましょう
In the future this is September 2010
今後、これは 2010 年 9 月です
Flooding situation of Typhoon Vanabye in Kaohsiung
台風19号ヴァナビーによる高雄市の浸水状況
will this happen
こうなるだろうか
still happens
まだ起こる
And it will be better than this in the future
そして将来的にはこれよりも良くなるでしょう
More severe floods will occur
さらに深刻な洪水が起こるだろう
what is this
これは何ですか
This is our Taipei metropolitan area
ここは私たちの台北都市圏です
Including Taoyuan around us
桃園も含めて
Our flooded landslides
私たちの浸水した地滑り
it risks this position
それはこの立場を危険にさらす
Then you can look inside your home
それから家の中を見てみましょう
Is it in these high-risk places?
こういった危険な場所にあるのでしょうか？
if it is a high place
高いところなら
we take the necessary precautions
私たちは必要な予防措置を講じます
That was March 2003
それは2003年3月のことでした
What reservoir is dry and almost no water can be seen in it?
乾燥していて水がほとんど見えない貯水池は何ですか?
Will there be a future or will there be a future
未来はあるのか、それとも未来はあるのか
It gives us the use of water resources
それは私たちに水資源の利用をもたらします
brought a big big impact
大きな大きな影響をもたらした
Then we faced this extreme situation
その後、私たちはこの極限状況に直面しました
it doesn't rain it's drought
雨が降っていません、干ばつです
When it rains, it rains again
雨が降るとまた雨が降る
what should we do
私たちは何をすべき
Then we actually have to start figuring out a way
それから実際に方法を考え始めなければなりません
Recently, the New Taipei City Government and the Pingtung County Government
最近では、新北市政府と屏東県政府が
are starting to promote the so-called sponge eco-city
いわゆるスポンジエコシティを推進し始めています
The sponge ecological city is Professor Liu Zhongming
海綿生態都市は劉忠明教授
Like some industries, they are promoting
一部の業界と同様に、彼らは次のことを推進しています。
He made all roads into permeable roads
彼はすべての道路を透水性のある道路に変えた
when it rains heavily
激しい雨が降ったとき
turned into a factory facility to allow it to counterbalance
バランスをとるために工場施設に改造されました
when it's not raining
雨が降っていないとき
these this
これらはこれ
The water born under the road is our natural reservoir
道路の下で生まれた水は私たちの自然の貯水池です
If you say that we put this permeable road
この透水性の道路を置いたと言うなら
only one meter
たった1メートル
Then the water permeability is only 30%
その場合、透水率はわずか30％です
if our six degrees tongtong zone does
私たちの6度のトントン地域がそうなれば
we increase the storage capacity of more than one whole reservoir
複数の貯水池全体の貯留容量を増やします
So the benefits it brings are very, very high
したがって、それがもたらすメリットは非常に高いです
even better is
さらに良いのは
It also has a cooling effect at high temperatures
高温時の冷却効果もあります
let's make our city it's not so hot
暑くない街にしましょう
It also soothes us when the temperature is high
気温が高いときにも癒されます
This is what we need to do in the future
これが将来私たちがしなければならないことです
we need to turn our homes
私たちは家を変える必要がある
Let our country start to reduce redness towards these disaster prevention in the future
我が国も今後、これらの防災に向けて赤み軽減に着手しましょう
There is also the direction of high temperature resistance to strive to promote
高温耐性の向上を目指すという方向性もあります。
our election is over
私たちの選挙は終わりました
But we can still tell our representatives
しかし、私たちはまだ代表者に伝えることができます
our government officials
私たちの政府関係者
We must start changing the way our country is built
私たちは国の建設方法を変え始めなければなりません
more importantly
さらに重要なことには
we must not ignore
私たちは無視してはなりません
Our Taiwan is a congenital earthquake is very frequent
私たちの台湾は先天的に地震が非常に頻繁に起こります
And where the risk is very high
そしてリスクが非常に高い場合
Taiwan has so many earthquakes
台湾は地震が多い
These are the so-called activity components announced by the government.
これらは政府が発表したいわゆる活動要素です。
These places tell you
これらの場所が教えてくれます
don't live
生きてはいけない
why
なぜ
Because live bomb city is the most dangerous place
生きた爆弾都市が最も危険な場所だから
it's a cartoon
それは漫画です
This cartoon tells us that
この漫画が教えてくれるのは、
before the earthquake
地震の前に
where do you build a house
どこに家を建てますか
you feel good
あなたは良い気分です
But when the earthquake happened
しかし、地震が起こったとき、
Although Zhenyang is here
鎮陽はここにいるのに
It's actually where the fault leaks that it hurts the most.
実際、最もダメージを受けるのは、障害が漏れている場所です。
because the crust shifts
地殻が変わるから
the entire crust on both sides
両面の生地全体
Its height difference will be much different
身長差がかなり違うだろう
energy along the fault
この断層に沿ったエネルギー
The place where the distribution is cast is the most
配信が行われている場所が一番多いです
So this place hurts the most
だからここが一番痛い
we can take a look
見てみましょう
The last time this build-up earthquake
前回この蓄積地震は
this is the case
これは事実です
This is the Wheel Spectrum tomography where it's located
これは、ホイール スペクトル断層撮影装置が配置されている場所です。
after it happened
それが起こった後
You can see it's wind source
風源であることがわかります
where its fault passes
その過失がどこに行くのか
The building responds to the sound
建物が音に反応する
If you are buying at this place
この場所で買うなら
There is no way to undo your damage
ダメージを元に戻す方法はありません
This is the Tiny Wind Bridge. It's broken.
これは小さな風の橋、壊れています
This is Shigang Dam
ここは石江ダムです
it can't exist
それは存在できません
such a solid structure
こんなにしっかりした構造
It has no way to resist the fault
障害に抵抗する方法はありません
let alone us
私たちどころか
so be careful
ので注意してください
Our house must never be built on a fault
私たちの家は決して断層の上に建ててはなりません
on top of our three floors
私たちの3つのフロアの上に
how do we know
どうやって知ることができますか
when the earthquake happened
地震が起こったとき
What measures are we going to take?
どのような対策を講じるのでしょうか？
The first one we will start ourselves
最初は自分たちで始めます
Prepare a shelter bag
避難袋を用意しましょう
Not enough for the elders in our family
私たちの家族の年長者には十分ではありません
sound kid
音誘兒
and place it in an easily accessible location
そしてそれをアクセスしやすい場所に置きます
Our secretariat colleague
私たちの事務局の同僚
When our luck opened up last year
去年私たちの運が開けたとき
I thoughtfully made this emergency for everyone
私は皆のためにこの緊急事態を考えて作りました
This card from the Refuge Pack
避難パックのこのカード
it tells us
それは私たちに伝えます
What kind of life support should we prepare
どのような生命維持装置を準備すればよいか
medical lighting for emergency
緊急用医療照明
advance letter of communication personal
個人的な事前連絡レター
usually when you get ready
通常、準備ができたときに
once it happens
それが起こったら
you won't keep
あなたは守らないでしょう
And you gotta know before it happens
そして、それが起こる前に知っておく必要があります
What should we do after it happens
そうなった後はどうすればいいのか
if you didn't get it just now
今理解できなかったら
It's ok when we go out later
後で出かけるときは大丈夫です
Get another copy with our secretariat colleague
事務局の同僚と一緒にもう 1 部入手してください
This is the Zhuang'an Geological Survey Institute of the Ministry of Economic Affairs
ここは経済部荘安地質調査所です。
its a web page
そのページの一つ
in the upper right corner of its web page
Web ページの右上隅にある
There is a country's geological regulations and customs
その国の地質学的規制や習慣がある
Integrated query system with geological data
地質データを使用した統合クエリ システム
You go to this page and open
このページにアクセスして開きます
Comb your home address in
自宅の住所を調べてみる
you can know your home address
自宅の住所を知ることができます
Are there active faults nearby?
近くに活断層はありますか？
Is there a downhill slope
下り坂はありますか
Are there any three risks of landslides occurring?
土砂崩れが起こる危険性は3つありますか？
It's actually a really good physical exam
それは実際には本当に良い身体検査です
Tell us if our home is safe
私たちの家が安全かどうか教えてください
this is let us
これは私たちにしましょう
Our government has integrated all these data
私たちの政府はこれらすべてのデータを統合しました
so that everyone can use
誰もが使えるように
So you must make good use of it
だからそれをうまく活用しなければなりません
If it is not convenient for you to buy a house online
ネットで家を買うのが不便な場合
You just download the software called Di Zero Zero
Di Zero Zeroというソフトウェアをダウンロードするだけです
put it in your phone
携帯電話に入れてください
Land zero zero, you just need to put it in the future
ランドゼロゼロ、未来に置けばいいだけ
when you go to buy a house
家を買いに行くとき
You stand right where your building is
あなたは建物がある場所に立っています
it tells you if there is an active fault nearby
近くに活断層があるかどうかを教えてくれる
how far is it
どのくらい遠いですか
Will there be a downhill slope?
下り坂はあるでしょうか？
will there be something else
他に何かあるでしょうか
these are for you to tell you
これらはあなたに伝えるためのものです
Technology we can now master
私たちが今習得できるテクノロジー
Help us avoid and prepare for these natural disasters
これらの自然災害の回避と備えにご協力ください
It's actually very, very important
実はとてもとても重要なことなのです
So we now say
そこで私たちは今こう言います
Our environment has changed a lot
私たちの環境は大きく変わりました
our risk is very high
私たちのリスクは非常に高いです
But the technology we have now is unimaginable in the past
しかし、私たちが今持っているテクノロジーは、昔では想像もできなかったものです
We can use this technology to protect ourselves
私たちはこのテクノロジーを利用して自分自身を守ることができます
Now the recent central seven areas and world digital technology
今、最近の中心7分野と世界のデジタル技術
Another app for earthquake disaster prevention players has been developed
地震防災プレイヤーのためのアプリがまた開発されました
Everyone can download it in your mobile phone
誰でも携帯電話にダウンロードできます
When downloading when there is an earthquake
地震発生時にダウンロードする場合
especially during earthquakes
特に地震の時は
it will tell you where it happened
それがどこで起こったかを教えてくれるでしょう
how big is it
それはどれくらい大きいですか
If it happened in a place far away
もしそれが遠く離れた場所で起こったなら
when it happens
それが起こったとき
can give us some early warning
早期に警告を与えることができる
in terms of positive earthquakes
正の地震に関して
It happened on September 21, 1999 at this Nantou positive time
それは1999年9月21日、この南投の前向きな時期に起こりました。
21 seconds later
21秒後
This destructive shock wave has only come to our Taipei
この破壊的な衝撃波は私たちの台北にだけやって来ました
21 seconds
21秒
You receive it as soon as it happens
発生したらすぐに受け取ります
You can do a lot of things in 21 seconds
21秒でいろんなことができる
So don't celebrate
だから祝わないで
Recently, the Fire Department of the Ministry of Earthquakes also established a Taiwan earthquake network
最近、地震省消防署も台湾地震ネットワークを設立しました。
So everyone can also go to the anti-seismic network
みんなも耐震ネットワークに行きましょう
It tells us that the computer
それは、コンピューターが
You must do three things well
3つのことをしっかりやらなければなりません
The first one must get down
最初の人は降りなければなりません
The second is to find a place to cover early in the morning
2つ目は、早朝にカバーできる場所を見つけることです
The third must be steady
3番目は安定している必要があります
after the earthquake pot
地震ポットの後
Let's move on to the next step
次のステップに進みましょう
in kengren.com
kengren.com 内
It has vibrations before we do things to prepare
準備をする前に振動があります
How do we take refuge when it is confirmed?
それが確認された場合、どのように避難すればよいでしょうか？
after proof
証明後
what should we pay attention to
何に注意すべきか
even provide rescue
救助も提供する
it's all we can do
それが私たちにできるすべてです
everyone must go in
誰もが入らなければなりません
then do some
それから何かをしてください
Download this useful information
この役立つ情報をダウンロードしてください
Finally I want to tell you
最後に伝えたいのは
you will manage money you will not be poor
あなたはお金を管理するでしょう、あなたは貧乏ではありません
you can draw you can't mess
絵を描くことはできますが、台無しにすることはできません
you are ready you will not be busy
準備はできています、忙しくはなりません
then i will tell you
それなら教えます
Facing the environmental crisis
環境危機に直面する
Of course it's scary. There are many challenges.
もちろん怖いですし、課題もたくさんあります。
But if we are ready
しかし、準備ができていれば
we won't die
私たちは死なない
Not only us personally
私たち個人だけではなく、
Our house is still like this
我が家はまだこんな感じです
Our country is like this
我が国はこんな感じです
So in the end I'll tell you
だから最後に言っておきます
Seven red brain words, it brings a great impact, very deep
7つの赤い脳の言葉、それは大きな影響をもたらします、非常に深い
its impact on our future
私たちの未来への影響
is unimaginable
想像を絶する
Our Taiwan needs each of us
私たちの台湾は私たち一人一人を必要としています
work together to build it
協力してそれを構築する
make it more complete
より完全なものにする
Taiwan will definitely change in the future
台湾はこれから必ず変わる
we can't stop
私たちは止まらない
But we can be in the process of changing in Taiwan
しかし、台湾では変化の過程にある可能性があります
make our home
私たちの家を作る
Dayuan is safer
大園のほうが安全
we are in energy
私たちはエネルギーの中にいます
Food Sanitation Water quality sources
食品衛生 水質源
Everyone can play a force
誰もが力を発揮できる
No matter what profession you do
どんな職業に就いても
you can all in this
これですべてができます
do our part
私たちの役割を果たす
more importantly
さらに重要なことには
Our future land plan
私たちの将来の土地計画
where the embankment was dug
堤防が掘られた場所
easy place along the water
水沿いのわかりやすい場所
place of fault
故障箇所
how can we avoid
どうすれば避けられるでしょうか
how to build
建て方
how to plan
どのように計画するか
all of us now
私たち全員が今
everyone can think
誰もが考えることができる
can work hard
一生懸命働くことができる
That's all for my sharing today
今日の共有はこれで終わりです
Thank you very much everyone
みなさん、本当にありがとうございました
I also hope to bring you some connections
また、何かご縁があれば幸いです
i want to drink first
まずは飲みたい
i don't know how
方法がわかりません
I personally think
個人的には思う
many friendships
たくさんの友情
perhaps
多分
can absorb more or less
多かれ少なかれ吸収できる
Then
それから
can also
こともできます
do it yourself
自分でやれ
That
それか
we open this now
今これを開きます
please
お願いします
i want to ask a question
私は質問をしたいです
that is
あれは
pacific ocean
太平洋
Continental
コンチネンタル
actually
実際
pacific ocean
太平洋
Antarctic ice melts as temperatures rise
気温上昇で南極の氷が溶ける
Melting causes sea-level temperatures to rise
融解により海面温度が上昇する
Then if we use another principle to deduce
次に、別の原理を使用して推論すると、
In the 17th century in Taiwan, the temperature should have been very low
17世紀の台湾では気温は非常に低かったはずです
So the ice at the north and south poles melts
それで北極と南極の氷が溶ける
From these four hundred years, one thing is
この四百年から一つ言えることは、
Discovery of seawater retreat in port
港内で海水の退避跡を発見
So in this way, the past few years
こうしてここ数年、
Is it possible for us now to let
今私たちにそれは可能ですか？
Taiwan returned to the temperature dropped to
台湾は気温が下がって戻ってきました
Let me talk about that first, is it because
まずそれについて話させてください。
Diving in the port and ice in the North and South Poles
北極と南極の港と氷でのダイビング
Dissolution is related
解散も関係あるよ
Dissolving causes the water level to drop
溶けると水位が下がります
then rise
それから上がる
Rising temperatures cause sea level water to rise
気温の上昇により海面水位が上昇する
Is this the principle
これが原則ですか
I said you should understand
理解すべきだと言いました
Thanks
ありがとう
i need to explain
説明する必要があります
When Zheng Chenggong landed in Taiwan
鄭成功が台湾に上陸したとき
At that time, it was the small soldier flag
当時は小兵旗だった
Taiwan's climate is colder than ours today
今日の台湾の気候は我が国よりも寒いです
It will snow in winter
冬には雪が降ります
like we are now
今の私たちのように
But after these 400 years
しかし、この400年の時を経て、
The influence of our braining
私たちの脳の影響
we have started
私たちは始めました
It is completely different from Zheng Chenggong's era
鄭成功の時代とは全く違う
At that time our Taiwan was like Kyoto today
当時の私たちの台湾は今の京都のようなものでした
Now our Taiwan is like Manila in the past
今の私たちの台湾は昔のマニラのようなものです
In the future we will be like this Jakarta
将来はこんなジャカルタになるだろう
So in this warming process
したがって、この温暖化プロセスでは
Sea level is actually rising gradually
実は海面は徐々に上昇している
You just said that in dry mouth
君は口が乾いてそう言っただけだよ
we see this water level it has some changes
この水位が見えますが、いくつかの変化があります
some places will drop this
いくつかの場所ではこれをドロップします
That has something to do with the changes in this area
それはこの地域の変化と関係がある
what else
ほかに何か
with our alpine one
私たちのアルパインのものと
Chongshi related
崇史関連
let us western plains
西部の平原に行こう
Its achievements are getting wider and wider
その成果はますます広がっています
But now the situation has started to reverse
しかし今、状況は逆転し始めています
with this sea level
この海面だと
rapid rise in warming
温暖化の急速な進行
Achievements that Takayama has enriched
高山が積み上げてきた功績
Can't keep up with the rate of sea level rise
海面上昇の速度に追いつけない
So the sea level will start flooding in the future
つまり、海面は将来的に洪水が始まるでしょう
In fact, our current Yanchao Station
実は、現在の延潮駅は
Our record of real cool tests
私たちの本当に素晴らしいテストの記録
Kaohsiung Port is now a year
高雄港は今年で1年になります
What is the rate at which its seawater rises
海水の上昇速度はどれくらいですか
0.7 cm
0.7cm
The 0.4 cm we just saw
先ほど見た0.4cm
Our Kaohsiung is 0.7 cm
私たちの高雄は0.7センチメートルです
Hsinchu cloth 1 cm
新竹布 1cm
1 year now
現在1年
Penghu is 1.7 cm
澎湖は1.7センチです
This is the Yanchao station we use now
これが私たちが今使っている塩潮駅です
The observed rate of sea level rise
観測された海面上昇率
So what I'm saying is
それで、私が言っていることは、
when warming
温めるとき
When the edge of the two levels disappears
2つのレベルの境界が消えるとき
Global sea levels will rise
世界の海面は上昇する
Our Taiwan is in a rising sea level
私たちの台湾は海面上昇中です
relatively high place
比較的高い場所
In the past, the climate will be cold or warm
過去には、気候は寒かったり暖かかったりするでしょう
But this cyclical change is now gone
しかし、この循環的な変化は今では消えています
We only have one way now
今は一つの道しかない
and it's getting faster
そしてそれはますます速くなっている
So looking at the long-term trend
したがって、長期的な傾向を見ると、
The situation we are facing is completely different from the past.
私たちが直面している状況は過去とはまったく異なります。
Thank you teacher for your wonderful speech
先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
What I want to ask is this
私が聞きたいのはこれです
In fact, these years
実はここ数年、
The warming news and scientific reports you talked about today
今日あなたが話した暖かいニュースと科学的報告
have heard
聞いた
But on the other hand, it is also heard that some scholars
しかし一方で、一部の学者はこう言っているとも聞く。
They claim they also present scientific evidence
彼らは科学的証拠も提示していると主張している
say these things we face today
私たちが今日直面しているこれらのことを言ってください
It's actually a natural part of the earth.
それは実際には地球の自然の一部です。
Instead of really needing to control industry to curb desire
欲望を抑えるために実際に業界を制御する必要があるのではなく
Be able to
できる
Suppressing things, so he said that everyone can continue to develop industries and continue to use energy without worrying
物事を抑制することで、誰もが安心して産業を発展させ、エネルギーを使い続けることができると述べた
but
しかし
Apparently, we didn't introduce to us today what are the main views of the opposing side.
どうやら、今日は相手側の主な視点が何であるかを紹介していませんでした。
I don't know the parties, please tell us what their opinions are
当事者は知りませんが、意見を聞かせてください
Then let's say your opinion is
それでは、あなたの意見はこうだとしましょう
How to refute their views, thank you
彼らの意見に反論する方法、ありがとう
Go past this Cheo to warm this
これを温めるためにこのチェオを通り過ぎてください
When this issue just happened
この問題が起こったばかりのとき
That is, I just got from the institute
つまり、研究所から来たばかりです
when I just graduated
卒業したばかりのとき
back then we said warming
当時は温暖化って言ってた
at a scientific meeting
科学会議で
our reaction
私たちの反応
Only about 5% agree
約5%しか同意していない
We were a minority
私たちは少数派でした
To this day, some people still think that
今でもそう思っている人がいる
warming is an illusion
温暖化は幻想だ
it is the natural cycle of the earth
それは地球の自然なサイクルです
An important part of natural cycle changes
自然サイクルの変化の重要な部分
But the remaining 5% agree
しかし残りの5%は同意している
This endorsed has become 95%
この支持率は95%になりました
I just feel this warming
この温暖化を感じているだけです
already a serious problem
すでに深刻な問題になっている
it's science
それは科学です
on this topic
このトピックにおいて
we see very different
私たちは全く違うものを見ています
I'm on this topic
私はこの話題についています
It's just over 30 years
30年ちょっと経ちますね
I just saw it turn it over
それがすべてをひっくり返すのを見たばかりです
The second means
2番目の意味は
in the history of the earth
地球の歴史の中で
we really see
私たちは本当に見ています
saw this it was high and low
これを見た、高かったり低かったり
it has ups and downs
浮き沈みがある
it has ice periods and warm periods
氷期と温暖期がある
like I just showed you
先ほど見せたもののように
400,000 years old record
40万年の記録
but it has a characteristic
しかし、それには特徴があります
what characteristics
どのような特徴があるのか
it's all flat
すべて平らです
because of the long-term trend
長期的な傾向があるため
it can go up and down
それは上がったり下がったりすることができます
But its trend must be flat
しかし、その傾向は横ばいでなければなりません
it won't have a way
それは仕方がないだろう
But today we see warming is not
しかし今日では、温暖化はそうではないことがわかります。
Warming it really has a direction
温めることには本当に方向性がある
And there is not only one direction
そして方向性は一つだけではありません
It reverses the changes that our planet should have had
それは私たちの惑星が持つべき変化を逆転させます
According to this, now we understand scientifically
これによると、現在では科学的に理解されています。
If it were not for our
私たちのことがなかったら
environmental impact
環境への影響
We changed the atmosphere inside
社内の雰囲気を変えました
Concentration of warm oxidation
温酸化濃度
We should now start entering
今から入力を始めましょう
next ice age
次の氷河期
then our weather today
それから今日の天気
actually better than this
実際にはこれよりも優れています
It's even colder when it's successful
成功するとさらに寒い
to achieve such a situation
そのような状況を達成するために
There is a very basic condition
非常に基本的な条件があります
The concentration of warm oxygen in our atmosphere
大気中の温酸素の濃度
cannot exceed 240 units
240単位を超えることはできません
we can see today
私たちは今日見ることができます
During this industrial revolution
この産業革命の中で
we are all here
私たちは皆ここにいます
almost 280 units
約280台
at that moment
その瞬間に
without human influence
人間の影響なしに
without us causing so much disruption
私たちがそれほど大きな混乱を引き起こすことなく
It will slowly drop from 280
280から徐々に下がっていきます
Then as long as it reaches 240
あとは240に達する限り
According to our current model
現在のモデルによると
we can know that
私たちはそれを知ることができます
It's starting to enter this next ice age.
次の氷河期が始まります。
Now we don't have this chance
今、私たちにはこのチャンスはありません
We are now at 400
今は400です
So according to the present earth
つまり、現在の地球によれば、
This accumulated thermal energy
この蓄積された熱エネルギーが
then it hits
それからヒットします
All we can do now is say
今私たちにできることは言うことだけです
can we do some braking
ブレーキをかけてもいいですか
What is the warming like today?
今日の温暖化はどうですか？
actually like a car
実際に車のように
This car is not on the train tracks
この車両は線路上にありません
it is on a hillside
それは丘の中腹にあります
rush down
急いで降りる
Then we are actually doing the brakes now.
それから、今は実際にブレーキをかけているところです。
We want the kinetic energy of the car to go down
車の運動エネルギーを下げたい
lower it
それを下げます
even able to stop
止めることさえできる
We also hope that one day it can return
私たちはまた、いつかそれが戻ってくることを願っています
Now we are all here
今、私たちは皆ここにいます
still in the downhill phase
まだ下り坂段階にある
So I hope everyone must work together
だからみんなで協力してほしいと思う
We let this downhill rate get lower and lower
この下り坂の速度をどんどん低くしていきます
And hope one day it can stop
そしていつかそれが止まることを願っています
even reversed
逆でも
This almost changes the target to
これによりターゲットがほぼ変更されます
205 trips reduced to 141 meals
205 回の旅行を 141 食に削減
I don't have any expectations at all
全く期待してないんだけど
because developing countries
発展途上国だから
Absolute need to increase energy use and CO2 emissions
エネルギー使用量とCO2排出量を増やすことが絶対に必要
it is impossible to avoid
避けることは不可能です
Continental from 2000 to 2015
2000 年から 2015 年までのコンチネンタル
This adds 5 billion tonnes to emissions
これにより排出量が50億トン増加します
so like india start today
インドのように今日から始めましょう
I believe between 35 years
35歳の間だと思う
India alone will add 5 billion tonnes to emissions
インドだけでも50億トンの排出量が追加される
and Southeast Asia
そして東南アジア
there are other countries
他の国もあります
Africa
アフリカ
Unless they stay forever in this inhuman life today
彼らが今日のこの非人間的な生活に永遠に留まらない限り
2.5 billion people in the world each year
毎年、世界で25億人が
Currently lives by hacking
現在ハッキングして生きています
more deaths per year
年間死亡者数が増える
because of climate respiratory
気候のせいで呼吸器系
because chopping leftovers for cooking
残り物を切って料理するから
1.5 million more deaths
死者も150万人増える
these poor countries
これらの貧しい国々
They are here in 20 30 years 30 50 years
彼らは20年後、30年後、30年後、50年後もここにいます
Must have a lot of energy usage
エネルギーの使用量が多いはずだ
and produce more and more carbon dioxide
そして二酸化炭素がどんどん発生します
Absolutely absolutely impossible to stay at 141 tons
141トンを維持するのは絶対に不可能
I can tell any of you
誰にでも言えます
I'm certainly alive until 2050
2050年まではきっと生きてる
I can agree with our purple grandson
私たちの紫色の孫の意見に同意します
Impossible at 141t
141tでは無理
This is a completely unrealistic goal
これはまったく非現実的な目標です
and it's inhumane
そしてそれは非人道的です
Those poor countries call him
貧しい国々は彼をこう呼びます
You can't burn briquettes if you chop stubble today
今日は無精ひげを切ったら練炭は燃やせないよ
Can't burn kerosene
灯油は燃やせない
You can't ride a motorcycle if you ride a cart
カートに乗ったらバイクには乗れない
stay in this situation forever
いつまでもこの状況に留まる
There may be more than a hundred
百以上あるかもしれない
This practice is completely inhumane
この行為は完全に非人道的です
This is the first one
これが最初のものです
The second one was last year
2回目は去年のものです
Because of the current cost of technology
現在のテクノロジーのコストのせいで
The technology is quite high
技術はかなり高いです
Losses due to natural disasters last year
昨年の自然災害による損失
was the lowest in seven years
過去7年間で最低だった
As you should know, it's only 89 billion U.S. dollars
ご存知のとおり、それはわずか 890 億米ドルです
So although the number of times reaches 1000
なので回数は1000回に達しますが
But property damage was the lowest in seven years.
しかし物的被害は過去７年間で最低だった。
So I think it's okay not to worry too much about these issues.
したがって、これらの問題についてはあまり心配しなくても大丈夫だと思います。
Xia Tian said that he has not changed to one meter taller
夏天さんは身長が1メートルも高くなったわけではないと語った
I think it's probably because I personally think it's impossible to hide
おそらく個人的には隠すのは不可能だと思っているからだと思います
That is 210 years more than one meter
1メートルを超えるのは210年です
Maybe a little more, probably can't hide
たぶんもう少し、おそらく隠すことはできない
because we later
なぜなら私たちは後で
It can be seen that it is always 21 billion to 31 billion
常に 210 億から 310 億であることがわかります
It is absolutely impossible to have a day of 14 billion
1日140億なんて絶対に無理
That is to say, it is impossible within fifty years
つまり50年以内は無理
absolutely impossible
絶対に無理
And it's inhumane to ask me to say it
そして私にそれを言うように求めるのは非人道的です
you stop forcing those
それらを強制するのはやめてください
A man who cuts his fortune will always cut his fortune, and a man who rides a bicycle will always ride a bicycle
財産を削る者は常に財産を削り、自転車に乗る者は常に自転車に乗ります。
it's impossible
それは不可能だ
So what we have to do is how to say
それで私たちがしなければならないのは、どう言うかです
It should be said that one meter in the future
1メートル先というべきか
In 2000 we rose one meter above the sea
2000 年に私たちは海抜 1 メートルに上昇しました
We can also get a good
私たちも良いものを手に入れることができます
It's not that big of a deal, like the Dutch ones.
オランダのような大したことではない。
An average of one meter faster at the beach
ビーチでは平均1メートル速くなりました
what you should do is rich
あなたがすべきことは豊かなことです
do what you should do
やるべきことをやる
or content coupons
またはコンテンツクーポン
There are various ways to deal with
いろいろな対処法がありますが、
So the sea is raised by one meter
それで海は1メートル高くなります
not a big problem
大きな問題ではない
other extreme changes in climate
その他の極端な気候変化
We want high mountain areas that are not suitable for people to sweep and rent horses
人が住むのに適さない高山地帯に掃き掃除や馬のレンタルをしてほしい
right
右
it's impossible
それは不可能だ
What our earthquake station just said
私たちの地震観測所が今言ったこと
If it is above the seismic station, of course the house should not be built.
地震観測所より上であれば、当然家を建てるべきではありません。
So this is what we want to emphasize
これが私たちが強調したいことです
But let me emphasize one more thing
しかし、もう一つ強調させてください
141 tons to Master 2 in 2050
2050年にマスター2まで141トン
Absolutely absolutely absolutely will not bear to do it
絶対に絶対に我慢できない
Thanks
ありがとう
This mentions two points
これは2つの点について言及しています
I am very careful
私はとても気をつけています
and also very important
そしてまた非常に重要です
The first one is the amount of soup we will drain in the future.
1つ目は今後排出するスープの量です。
Will it reach us today
今日は届くでしょうか
The goals we set at the Paris climate conference
パリ気候会議で設定した目標
Let's keep our temperature from rising two degrees
気温が2度上がらないようにしましょう
It can even be from 1.5 degrees to 1.5 degrees.
1.5度から1.5度までの場合もあります。
Then let our energy saving can reach the target
それでは、省エネを目標に達成しましょう
Then with the existing technology, the existing politics
そして既存のテクノロジーと既存の政治
their mode of operation
彼らの動作モード
We all say it's an impossible task
私たちは皆、それは不可能な仕事だと言う
In fact, this is ignoring us humans
実際、これは私たち人間を無視しています
willing to sacrifice this
これを犠牲にするつもりです
You all know that we humans are like ordinary animals
皆さんもご存知の通り、私たち人間は普通の動物です
The difference is
違いは
we can change ourselves
私たちは自分自身を変えることができます
That is the game theory I just mentioned
それが先ほど述べたゲーム理論です
What is the biggest point of Game Theory?
ゲーム理論の最大のポイントは何ですか?
you have to put yourself down first
まず自分を下げなければなりません
willing to sacrifice
犠牲をいとわない
then this is paris river will it be able to pass
じゃあここはパリ川だ、渡れるだろうか
More than 100 countries around the world can
世界中の100カ国以上が可能です
can reach a consensus
合意に達することができる
The most important thing is that everyone is willing to compromise
最も重要なことは、誰もが進んで妥協することです
willing to back down
喜んで後退する
Compromise and retreat is just the beginning
妥協と撤退は始まりにすぎない
It may be difficult at first
最初は難しいかも知れません
But as soon as it starts
でも始まるとすぐに
it can go in this powerful direction
この強力な方向に進むことができます
keep moving
動き続ける
so i don't think
だから私はそう思わない
think it's an impossibility
それは不可能だと思う
it's a tough
それは大変です
it's a very difficult goal
それはとても難しい目標だ
but not an impossible
でも不可能ではない
The first is to say
一つ目は言うことです
We must strengthen the common good
私たちは共通善を強化しなければなりません
Just like this gentleman said
この紳士が言ったように
If we only think about ourselves
自分のことだけを考えていたら
do not consider others
他人のことを考えない
this won't work
これはうまくいきません
We must first consider people
まず人間について考えなければなりません
just like these
ちょうどこれらのように
those poor countries
あの貧しい国々
if we could reach out
手を差し伸べることができたら
we would like to help him
私たちは彼を助けたいと思っています
there is hope for this
これには希望がある
And this requires us to pay a price and sacrifice
そしてそのためには代償と犠牲を払う必要があります
The second is to say
2つ目は、こう言うことです
after warming
温めた後
The amount of our losses will be reduced
私たちの損失額は減ります
Looks like the number of natural disasters
自然災害の多さのようです
Asymmetrical
非対称
There is actually a reason for this
実はこれには理由があるのです
what is the reason
理由は何ですか
because we are ready
準備はできていますので
when we are ready
準備ができたら
Our damage will actually be reduced
私たちの被害は実際に軽減されます
very very many
非常非常多
Also an earthquake
地震も
Happened in Haiti only scale period
ハイチでのみ発生した規模期間
It caused more than hundreds of thousands of casualties
数十万人以上の死傷者を出した
But there was an earthquake in Chile
でもチリで地震がありました
It scales over 8
スケールは8以上です
is more than 30 times that of
の30倍以上です
But it killed only a few hundred people
でも死者は数百人だけだった
with not ready
準備ができていない
It's the difference between good and bad construction
それが良い建築と悪い建築の違いです
So today we just want to say
そこで今日私たちが言いたいのは、
We wish to say that these rich and powerful countries
私たちは、これらの豊かで強力な国々が、
well developed country
発展した国
be able to sacrifice a little more
もう少し犠牲を払うことができる
Then help these weak nations rise together
そして、これらの弱い国々が共に立ち上がるのを助けてください
then our country
それから私たちの国
There is hope in our world
私たちの世界には希望があります
that's what i mean
それが私の言いたいことです
This requires each of us to work hard
そのためには私たち一人ひとりが一生懸命働く必要があります
you can see
見ることができます
For example, we have a city bureau in Taiwan
たとえば、台湾には市の支局があります。
This city bureau is here
この市役所はここにあります
Not the City Bureau of Kaohsiung
高雄市市局ではありません
It's the city bureau in Taitung
台東市の市役所です
Then it's just a vegetable seller
それではただの野菜売りです
its impact
その影響
can surpass many of us
私たちの多くを超えることができる
What's this
これは何ですか
is that it is willing to sacrifice
それは犠牲をいとわないということです
I think the greatest hope of our humanity today
今日の人類にとって最大の希望だと思います
right here
ここにあります
that's what i wish to say
それが私が言いたいことです
first of all of us
まずは私たちから
we need to know
私たちは知る必要がある
It's actually today that we see this climate change
この気候変動が実際に見られるのは今日です
It changes the future of our planet
それは私たちの地球の未来を変える
changed our lives
私たちの生活を変えました
it's like we got
まるで得たみたいだ
Cancer is not necessarily a terminal illness
がんは必ずしも末期の病気ではない
Come to cancer he will become terminally ill
癌になれば彼は末期の病気になるだろう
First we don't face him
まず私たちは彼と向き合わない
Second we don't treat him
第二に、私たちは彼を治療しません
The third one we don't change ourselves
3つ目は自分自身を変えないこと
so i wish to say
だから私は言いたいのです
through a share like this
このようなシェアを通じて
I hope you all recognize our
皆さんも私たちのことを認識していただければ幸いです
very challenging
たいへんやりがいがある
our difficulty
私たちの困難
but we don't despair
でも私たちは絶望しません
if we give up
私たちが諦めたら
is despair
絶望です
if we don't want to give up
諦めたくないなら
we are willing to sacrifice
私たちは喜んで犠牲を払います
we are willing to reach out
私たちは喜んで手を差し伸べます
we still have hope
私たちにはまだ希望がある
let's treat him
彼を治療しましょう
we change ourselves
私たちは自分自身を変えます
we don't think it's impossible
私たちはそれが不可能だとは思いません
today you can see say
今日、あなたは言うことができます
if we emit carbon
私たちが炭素を排出すると
so low
とても低い
of course it is possible
もちろん可能です
our energy
私たちのエネルギー
If new energy can be produced
新しいエネルギーが生み出せれば
There are new efficiencies
新たな効率性が生まれる
we really can
本当にできます
achieve this goal
この目標を達成する
This is my personal optimistic view
これは私の個人的な楽観的な見方です
so i think say
だから私は言うと思います
Changes in our humanity
私たちの人間性の変化
In fact, not only can
実際、できるだけでなく、
let's get there
そこに行きましょう
have a different future
違う未来がある
ask the director
監督に聞いてください
Hello everyone
こんにちは、みんな
My surname is Guo
私の姓は郭です
I'm going to ask a side question first
まず補足的な質問をさせていただきます
Have you learned about Amitou Buddha
阿弥陀仏についてご存知ですか？
this is not chinese
これは中国語ではありません
not Chinese
中国人ではない
I'm christian
私はクリスチャンです
I am god
僕は神だ
I'm asking this
私はこれを尋ねています
I will act first
まずは私が行動します
I watch TVBS TV with a few minutes of introduction
数分間の紹介付き TVBS テレビを見ています
like you go to japan to flood
洪水をしに日本に行くのと同じように
flooded the house
家が水浸しになった
people standing on the roof
屋根の上に立つ人々
he talks more
彼はもっと話します
He said that petrochemical leaf is a very greedy industry
彼は、石油化学リーフは非常に貪欲な産業だと言いました。
There is also news in recent days
最近のニュースでもあります
Said plastic bags in the ocean in a few years
数年後にはビニール袋が海に流されるとのこと
will be as much as fish
魚と同じくらいになるだろう
Look at the current situation of the color of the ocean
海の色の現状を見てください
then i have this video
それから私はこのビデオを持っています
I'll ask you again
もう一度聞いてみます
Units like environmental scientist Lin and Academia Sinica
中央研究院の環境科学者林氏などのユニット
Like Shida Environmental Pedagogy, as well as religious units
志田環境教育学や宗教団体のように
Like Daai TV Station, Mercy Forbidden Society, and Boguang Mountain
大愛テレビ局、慈悲厳禁協会、博光山など
Many units pay great attention to the environment
多くのユニットが環境に細心の注意を払っています
Environmental recycling made a lot of effort
環境リサイクルに力を入れました
But many units are also consuming a lot of resources
しかし、多くのユニットは大量のリソースを消費します
So the effort is wasted
だからその努力は無駄になる
The bottom is not enough to maintain this good environment
この良好な環境を維持するには底力だけでは十分ではありません
The main question I ask is to say
私の主な質問は次のとおりです
Do you know the American government and politics?
あなたはアメリカ政府と政治について知っていますか？
politics it is for the economic development of the country
政治は国の経済発展のためです
Yes, to provide the common people with a moderate life
そう、庶民に適度な生活を提供するためです
reduce employment, right?
雇用を減らしますよね？
This is very important
これはとても重要です
the problem is to say
問題は言うことです
Can it be evaluated from a scientific and rational point of view?
科学的・合理的な観点から評価できるのか？
How much material resources do ordinary people need for housing and transportation?
一般の人は住居や交通手段にどれだけの物質的資源を必要としますか?
how much to produce
どれくらい生産するか
If there is too much consumption, it is necessary to correct it through education
消費が多すぎる場合は教育を通じて是正する必要がある
That is the question I want to ask is whether the governments, politicians, and government officials of various countries can cooperate with environmental science and religious units
そこで私が聞きたいのは、各国の政府、政治家、役人が環境科学や宗教団体と協力できるかどうかということです。
Come to the real world to educate and correct the people's thoughts and life concepts, and only then can the real environment be achieved.
現実の世界に来て、人々の考えや人生概念を教育し、修正して初めて、現実の環境が達成されます。
Then my last suggestion is that Buddhism has been spread from India to China for more than 2000 years
そして私の最後の提案は、仏教は 2000 年以上にわたってインドから中国に伝わってきたということです。
Later, so many people in Taiwan also studied Buddhism.
その後、台湾でも多くの人が仏教を学びました。
Let's get back to the topic, shall we?
本題に戻りましょうか。
I can finish in about a minute
1分くらいで終わるよ
you talk for five minutes
あなたは5分間話します
Because this is the main problem
これが一番の問題だから
In the 1970s, there was a British historian, Dr. Toynbee
1970年代、イギリスの歴史家トインビー博士がいました。
He said that there are only two systems that can solve human problems, social problems, and earth problems in the 2 billion century
20億世紀の人類問題、社会問題、地球問題を解決できるシステムは2つしかない、と彼は言いました。
It is the education of Confucianism and the second Dacheng Buddhism
儒教と第二次大成仏教の教育です
So what does Buddhism talk about? It talks about all emptiness
では、仏教は何を語っているのでしょうか? 仏教はすべての空について語っています。
No amount of development
いくら開発してもダメ
not when people are together
人が一緒にいるときではない
I think a lot of people are raising their hands
たくさんの人が手を挙げていると思います
problem first
まず問題
Is this good?
これでいいですか？
we can end this speech first
まずこのスピーチを終わらせてもいいでしょう
Then if you have any questions, you can stay and I will answer them
それで、何か質問があれば、ここにいてもいいです、私が答えますよ
He just started
彼は始めたばかりです
ask the director
監督に聞いてください
Just now we saw the whip
たった今、マップウィップを見ました
I'm wondering if it's in the future
将来的にそうなるのか気になる
or come again in 2016
または 2016 年にまた来てください
Earthquakes will happen in Taiwan
台湾でも地震が起きるだろう
Because of the impact of climate warming
気候温暖化の影響により
Earthquakes will be more frequent
地震がもっと頻繁になるだろう
Then the haste of the earthquake will also increase, right?
そうなると地震の速さも増すでしょう？
Thanks
ありがとう
I think that from the past few decades in our
過去数十年間、私たちの社会では
For this area of ​​development
この開発分野については
The number of our earthquakes is increasing
地震の数は増加しています
But of course every year has its ups and downs
しかし、もちろん毎年浮き沈みがあります
Then it scales
それからスケールします
So if it's a trap, will the trap grow bigger?
では、それが罠だった場合、罠は大きくなるでしょうか？
the world is getting bigger
世界はますます大きくなっている
Taiwan will also be affected by this
台湾も影響を受けるだろう
But will it happen in 2016
しかし、それは2016年に起こるだろうか
we can't say
私たちは言えません
because we can't predict
予測できないから
Let's just say it tends to look like this
このように見える傾向があるとだけ言っておきましょう
we must be prepared for this
私たちはこれに備えなければなりません
can you say this
これを言えますか
so many people can leave first
とても多くの人が先に出発できる
i can stay
私は滞在できます
Then if there is a problem
それで問題があれば
we can be here
私たちはここにいることができます
i want to ask a little question
少し質問したいのですが
just as said before
前に言ったように
rain will increase
雨が増えるだろう
this is a trend
これはトレンドです
then ask
その後尋ねます
like desert areas and arid areas
砂漠地帯や乾燥地帯など
Is the rainfall also increasing?
雨量も増えてきているのでしょうか？
or is it more arid
それとももっと乾燥しているのでしょうか
this is a very good question
これはとても良い質問です
Academician Liu Shaochen was here last time
学者の劉少晨氏は前回ここに来ました
has said that he has been
彼はそう言った
we have two things to say
私たちには言いたいことが2つあります
First, the rainfall in global terms
まず、地球規模での降雨量です。
We don't see the obvious
私たちは明らかなことを見ていません
it is increasing
増えています
Its most important thing is that the rainfall intensity becomes very strong
最も重要なことは、降雨強度が非常に強くなるということです。
it gets very extreme
それは非常に極端になります
Academician Liu Shaocheng used data from land
学者のLiu Shaocheng氏は陸上のデータを使用した
tell us the rain doesn't look like it's increasing
雨は増えていないようだと言ってくれ
but i just told you
でも私はあなたに言ったばかりです
The humidity inside our Daji City is actually a lot
私たちの大吉市は実は湿気が多いのです
So the rainfall is actually increasing
つまり雨量は実際に増加している
It's just that the increase doesn't necessarily happen on land
ただ、増加は必ずしも陸上で起こるわけではありません
it may be in the sea
海の中にあるかも知れません
So I can only say that the change of rainfall is difficult to control
したがって、降雨量の変化を制御するのは難しいとしか言​​えません。
Some places increase and some places decrease
増えるところもあれば減るところもある
But the intensity of rainfall is increasing everywhere
しかし、どこでも雨の強さが増しています
Teacher, thank you for your wonderful speech today
先生、今日は素晴らしいお話をありがとうございました
In fact, you told us a very important concept is
実際、非常に重要な概念があると教えていただきました。
This group of global warming is past climate change
このグループの地球温暖化は過去の気候変動です
It takes tens of thousands of years and thousands of years to reach
到達するには何万年も何千年もかかる
Now it may be reached in just a hundred years
今ならあと100年以内に達成できるかもしれない
This is what we have to adjust and adapt to
これは私たちが調整して適応しなければならないことです
This is our concept today
これが今日の私たちのコンセプトです
The most important thing is that I want to ask the teacher a few questions
最も重要なことは、先生にいくつか質問したいことです
The first one is what you just said
1つ目はあなたが今言ったことです
Because of the relationship with Global Money
グローバルマネーとの関係で
So it will make Platonic Dynamic
つまりプラトニックダイナミックになります
so-called plate dynamics
いわゆるプレートダイナミクス
will intensify and cause an earthquake
地震が激化して地震を引き起こすだろう
But I don't think so
でも私はそうは思わない
because we have entered
私たちが入ったので
Because I'm not a researcher in this area
私はこの分野の研究者ではないので、
So I want to ask the teacher to say
そこで先生に聞きたいのですが、
When you study that terrestrial dynamics
地球の力学を研究すると
Is it because our world has entered into
私たちの世界が入ってきたからでしょうか？
A so-called plate activity cycle
いわゆるプレート活動サイクル
And with the so-called Global Money
そして、いわゆるグローバルマネーを使って
Actually it doesn't matter
実際にはそれは関係ありません
The first question I want to mention is this
私が言及したい最初の質問はこれです
The second question is about the number of typhoons
２番目の質問は台風の数についてです。
Last time Academician Liu still had that
前回、学者のリューはまだそれを持っていました
The former teacher Wu Junjie
元教師ウー・ジュンジエ
When they were talking about the number of typhoons
台風の数について話していたとき
actually they said
実際に彼らは言いました
Emmen's theory you have already talked about
すでに話したエメン理論
In fact, there is no substantial increase
実際には大幅な増加はない
What about your teacher just now?
今の先生はどうしましたか？
There is a large increase in the slideshow
スライドショーが大幅に増加しました
This is what I think is a bit of Crisis De Mar
これはちょっとしたクライシス・デ・マールだと思います
a problem place
問題のある場所
Or do we have different definitions
それとも違う定義があるのでしょうか
I will say it because you have a degree
学歴があるから言います
the number of your typhoon
あなたの台風の番号
It's because your intensity definition is different
強度の定義が違うからです
will increase or decrease
増えるか減るか
The third question is
3つ目の質問は、
Just now we talked about the rise in the temperature of the sea surface
先ほど海面水温の上昇の話をしましたが、
In fact, we are in the so-called
実際、私たちはいわゆる
In the atmosphere, we are talking next to me
隣で話している雰囲気
But we found that
しかし、私たちはそれを発見しました
Next to Wen Bo me is not where the sea temperature increase is the highest
文博の次は海水温の上昇が最も高い場所ではありません
I want to ask the teacher like this
先生にこんなふうに聞きたい
why is this the case
なぜそうなるのか
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
back from the third
3回目から戻って
Mr. Liu Shaocheng, the third one listed on the market, has already said
市場に上場している3番目の企業であるLiu Shaocheng氏はすでに次のように述べています。
Just this increase in sea temperature
たったこれだけの海水温の上昇
Typhoons may not happen
台風は来ないかもしれない
It also depends on the surrounding atmospheric conditions
周囲の大気条件にも左右されます
For example, the wind cuts a lot
たとえば、風がよく切れる
Therefore, the sea temperature condition is only a necessary condition that he must meet.
したがって、海水温の条件は満たさなければならない必要条件にすぎません。
Basic conditions but not necessarily a typhoon
基本条件だが台風とは限らない
In the long run, will the typhoon increase our current observation time?
長期的には、台風の影響で現在の観測時間は伸びるのでしょうか？
relatively short
比較的短い
so there is no definite answer
だから明確な答えはない
Didn't I just say that
さっき言ったじゃないですか
i mean his
つまり彼のことです
possible trend
考えられる傾向
This is still to be verified
これはまだ検証中です
so i can't say
だから言えない
Said the typhoon will definitely increase
台風は必ず増えるって言ってた
then strength it can get strong
そうすれば強さは強くなることができます
like the typhoon we just saw
さっき見た台風のように
in terms of energy
エネルギーの面で
what we're accumulating now on the surface
私たちが今地上に蓄積しているもの
How much is the accumulated energy in English
蓄積されたエネルギーは英語でいくら？
I can use another number
別の番号を使用できます
We just took the earthquake off the coast of Tohoku, Japan
東北地方沖で地震が起きたばかりです
energy scale
エネルギースケール
How much energy do we accumulate
私たちはどれだけのエネルギーを蓄積しているのでしょうか
More than 500,000
500,000以上
Do you think it will affect our earth?
それは私たちの地球に影響を与えると思いますか？
All Geophysical Dynamic
すべての地球物理学的動的
Right now our earth science has no answers
現時点では地球科学には答えがありません
Because our observation time is very short now
観測時間が非常に短いため
Our observations are not enough
私たちの観察だけでは十分ではありません
So we don't have an answer scientifically right now
したがって、現時点では科学的な答えはありません
But so much energy accumulates in this place
でも、この場所にはたくさんのエネルギーが溜まっている
you don't need to be precise
正確である必要はありません
Let's just intuitively say
直感的に言ってみましょう
we know it must have had an impact
それが影響を与えたに違いないことを私たちは知っています
It's just that the impact with this time
ただ今回の影響は
it will become more and more obvious
それはますます明らかになるだろう
Our answers will also become clearer
私たちの答えも明らかになるでしょう
just say that in the process
途中でそう言ってください
We still need to work hard to resolve
解決するにはまだ努力が必要です
where do they really go
彼らは本当にどこへ行くのですか
because I watched a lot
たくさん見ていたので
Yes they will come into their place
はい、彼らは彼らの場所にやって来ます
they will win their place
彼らは自分たちの地位を勝ち取るだろう
no answer
答えはありません
no answer so far
今のところ答えはありません
And what we see now is all on the outermost surface of the earth
そして私たちが今見ているものはすべて地球の最表面にあります
It's the atmosphere, the ocean and the very thin crust.
それは大気、海、そして非常に薄い地殻です。
The crust is already below 100 kilometers
地殻はすでに100キロメートル以下にある
So that's something we can't handle right now
だからそれは今は対処できないことなんだ
hello teacher sorry
こんにちは先生ごめんなさい
i want to ask two questions
2つの質問がしたいです
One is that just after I heard
一つは、聞いた直後のことです
Knowing that carbon dioxide seems to be responsible for the entire greenhouse effect
二酸化炭素が温室効果全体の原因であると思われることを知る
one main reason
一個最主要的原因
Then everyone is on the same thinking of carbon dioxide
そうすれば、二酸化炭素については誰もが同じ考えを持っています
Are there any scientific studies that say
という科学的研究はありますか？
For example, we are in addition to consistent carbon dioxide
たとえば、私たちは一貫した二酸化炭素に加えて、
basically think of it as an indoor greenhouse
基本的には屋内温室と考えてください。
Is it possible to say that there is a window on science
科学に窓があると言えるでしょうか？
Let nature let the heat of this gas out to outer space
このガスの熱を自然に宇宙に逃がしてもらいましょう
Is there any research in this area so that we can come from the root
この分野で根本から解決できるような研究はありますか?
To reduce the possibility of this happening in HEC
HEC でこのようなことが起こる可能性を減らすには
This is the first question
これが最初の質問です
The second question I just saw
先ほど見た 2 番目の質問
The teacher has a lot of data
先生はたくさんのデータを持っています
In this data
このデータでは
It's all based on data from the past few decades.
すべて過去数十年のデータに基づいています。
But is there another layer
しかし、別の層はありますか
For example, we lock in earthquakes above magnitude 7
たとえば、地震で閉じ込められたのは7レベル以上です
But various felt earthquakes below magnitude 7
しかし、マグニチュード7未満のさまざまな有感地震
These are all the data
これらがすべてのデータです
Big data is very popular now
今、ビッグデータがとても普及しています
Are we ignoring a section of the warning signs?
警告サインの一部を無視するつもりですか?
on science
科学について
bring us meaning
私たちに意味をもたらしてくれる
very good second question
とても良い2番目の質問
We are now targeting
私たちが今ターゲットにしているのは、
Those who have a direct impact on us at Level 7 or above
レベル7以上で我々に直接影響を与える者
Earthquake below magnitude 7
マグニチュード7以下の地震
Of course, its energy accumulation cannot be ignored
そのエネルギー蓄積は確かに無視できません
This we are on science
これが私たち科学です
Can't do it because the scale is too big
スケールが大きすぎて無理
Our data is really not enough
私たちのデータでは本当に十分ではありません
Our observations are also very limited
私たちの観察も非常に限られています
answer your first question
最初の質問に答えてください
sorry i need a moment
申し訳ありませんが、少し時間が必要です
carbon dioxide
二酸化炭素
carbon dioxide you just said
あなたが今言った二酸化炭素
It's actually a very good idea
実はとても良いアイデアなんです
It's carbon dioxide and we're all one now
それは二酸化炭素だ、そして私たちは今一つだ
hurt us the most
私たちを最も傷つけた
But if we can be creative
しかし、もし私たちが創造的になることができれば、
and then burn the carbon dioxide back
そして二酸化炭素を燃やして戻します
Even transforming into our creamy Nahua
クリーミーなナワにも変身
This is actually a subject that many of us are struggling with
実はこれは私たちの多くが悩んでいるテーマなのです
That's actually a very good
それは実際とても良いことです
The other is that our science uses the thermal energy accumulated on the surface of the earth
もう一つは、私たちの科学は地表に蓄積された熱エネルギーを利用しているということです。
be able to have a pipe to get it out
それを取り出すためのパイプを持っていることができる
That is impossible with the existing man-made technology
それは既存の人工技術では不可能です
Only like the 311 earthquake that occurred in the northeast of Japan last time
前回の東北地方で起きた311地震と同じように
We will actually observe when the earthquake occurs
地震が起きたら実際に観測してみます
The thermal energy of the earth's surface can go up to more than 400 kilometers outside the atmosphere
地表の熱エネルギーは大気圏外 400 キロメートル以上にまで及ぶことがある
This is what we can observe directly from Humanitarian Satellites
これは人道衛星から直接観察できるものです
The energy it releases is something that we humans cannot achieve.
それが放出するエネルギーは、私たち人間が達成できないものです。
I think this earth is actually it's me tuning
この地球は実は私がチューニングしているのだと思う
It is through such an earthquake, for example
それは、例えば、このような地震を通してです。
or other natural disasters that actually release energy
実際にエネルギーを放出するその他の自然災害
So the higher the energy, the more intense the earth's response
したがって、エネルギーが高くなるほど、地球の反応はより激しくなります。
Just like our high fever
私たちの高熱のように
We have to work hard to send this heat energy out
この熱エネルギーを送り出すために私たちは頑張らなければなりません
Our performance is very, very intense and extreme.
私たちのパフォーマンスは非常に激しく、極端です。
Ask the teacher, I just talked about that
先生に聞いてください、今その話をしたところです
The monkey fault in Taiwan is related to sea level rise
台湾のモンキー断層は海面上昇と関係している
Where are we going to find information on this?
これに関する情報はどこで入手できますか?
I mean it was released just now
つまり今発売されたばかりです
Can I ask the teacher to send you the materials again?
先生にもう一度資料を送ってもらうように頼んでもいいですか？
OK, the sea level rise is currently non-existent
OK、海面上昇は現在存在しない
That's because our current Yanchao data is actually very limited.
それは、現在の塩潮データが実際には非常に限られているためです。
But now there is a software on the Internet
しかし今はインターネット上にソフトウェアがあります
This software is called a trend of sea level rise
このソフトウェアは海面上昇の傾向と呼ばれます
Then you can just Google it
それならGoogleで調べてみてください
it just tells you
それはただあなたに言うだけです
It can only say static mock
静的モックとしか言えません
Ascent 1 meter 2 meters 5 meters 7 meters
上昇 1 メートル 2 メートル 5 メートル 7 メートル
Which places will be submerged
どの場所が水没するのか
it's just static
それはただ静的です
it can't tell you the future
未来を語ることはできない
By which year will it rise by how much
何年までにどれくらい上がるでしょうか
As for the living bomb layer, it's actually very easy.
アクティブ爆弾レイヤーに関しては、実際には非常に簡単です。
I just mentioned that there are two pages
先ほど2ページあると言いましたが、
A central geological shelf lock
一個中央地質架鎖
One is ground zero zero
一つはグラウンド・ゼロ・ゼロ
The central geological shelf locks the information on that webpage
中央の地質棚はそのウェブページ上の情報をロックします
is very complete
非常に完成度が高い
Then as long as you enter your home address in
次に、自宅の住所を入力する限り、
it will show you the map
地図が表示されます
Then the location of active faults can be clearly marked
そうすれば、活断層の位置を明確にマークできます
Then you look at the distance between your home and this active fault
次に、あなたの家とこの活断層の間の距離を見てください。
Usually if the distance is more than 100 meters
通常、距離が100メートル以上の場合
you can probably rest assured
おそらく安心できるでしょう
If you are within this 100 meters
この100メートル以内にいる場合
you have to be careful
あなたは注意する必要があります
If unfortunately you happen to be on this active fault
運悪くこの活断層の上にいたら
draw the words above that line
その線の上に単語を描画します
I advise you to move now
今すぐ移動することをお勧めします
Thank you Director Wang for your wonderful speech today
王監督、今日は素晴らしいスピーチをしていただきありがとうございました
Then I also brought you some messages to take home
それから、家に持ち帰るためのメッセージもいくつか持ってきました
That is to say, starting from the individual and everyone to take actions to save energy and reduce carbon
つまり、一人ひとりが、一人ひとりが、省エネ、炭素削減に向けた行動を起こすということです。
Then I just had one talking about this
それから、ちょうどこれについて話していることがありました
CO2 emissions impossible
CO2排出は不可能
I said it's impossible with current technology
今の技術では無理だと言いました
But you can see that many people are working hard today
でも、今日もたくさんの人が頑張っているのがわかります
we change our
私たちは私たちを変える
Lifestyles and communities that are changing energy
エネルギーを変えるライフスタイルとコミュニティ
If solar energy can really be developed to
太陽エネルギーが本当に開発できるなら
It is indeed possible to replace our carbon dioxide
私たちの二酸化炭素を置き換えることは確かに可能です
Can't say it's impossible, at least it can improve
不可能とは言えませんが、少なくとも改善は可能です
don't keep going up
上がり続けないでください
well thank you very much
ありがとうございます
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました